<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Flatfile Platform Changelog]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Notable additions and updates to the Flatfile platform]]></description>
        <link>https://flatfile.com</link>
        <image>
            <url>https://flatfile.com/favicon.jpg</url>
            <title>Flatfile Platform Changelog</title>
            <link>https://flatfile.com</link>
        </image>
        <generator>Flatfile RSS Generator</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 17:30:39 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>60</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Improved Data Clips Collaborator Experience]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Improved Data Clips Collaborator Experience</strong></p>
<p>We've enhanced the user experience in Data Clips by hiding the collaborator input when no space guests exist:</p>
<ul>
<li>The collaborator input is now automatically hidden in the Data Clip create modal when there are no space guests</li>
<li>Similarly, the collaborator section is hidden in the share modal when no guests are available</li>
<li>This provides a cleaner interface by only showing relevant options based on the current space context</li>
</ul>
<p>This improvement streamlines the Data Clips creation and sharing workflow by removing unnecessary UI elements when they're not applicable.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#04082025</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-04-08-2025-spaces-ui</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[spaces-ui]]></category>
            <pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Advanced Filters with Field Validation Status]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h2>description: &quot;New filtering capabilities to query by field validation status&quot;</h2>
<p><strong>Advanced Filters with Field Validation Status</strong></p>
<p>We've enhanced our filtering capabilities with a new Advanced Filters feature that supports querying by field validation status. This powerful addition allows you to build dynamic filters that combine field selection with validation checks.</p>
<p>Key improvements include:</p>
<ul>
<li>Support for the FFQL <code>is</code> operator with values of <code>error</code> and <code>valid</code></li>
<li>Ability to create complex filters targeting specific fields with validation issues</li>
<li>User-friendly interface for building advanced filter queries</li>
<li>Seamless integration with existing filtering capabilities</li>
</ul>
<p>For example, you can now easily find all records where a specific field (like &quot;email&quot;) has validation errors, or combine this with other conditions to create precise filters for your data cleanup workflows.</p>
<p>This feature is particularly useful for data quality management, allowing you to quickly identify and address problematic fields across your datasets.</p>
<p><img src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/4f7b1043-aba4-45c3-8557-bfa8e2a878b3" alt="Advanced Filters Demo"></p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#04082025</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-04-08-2025-title: Advanced Filters with Field Validation Status</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[title: Advanced Filters with Field Validation Status]]></category>
            <pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New row insertion feature in Flatfile's data tables.]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>New row insertion feature in Flatfile's data tables.</p>
<ul>
<li>Users can now add new rows by hovering over row dividers in the index column</li>
<li>An &quot;Insert row&quot; button appears when hovering between rows</li>
<li>Clicking the button adds a new row at the selected position</li>
<li>The feature provides a more intuitive way to add data at specific positions in a table</li>
</ul>
<p>This enhancement improves the user experience by making row insertion more discoverable and allowing precise control over where new rows are added in the dataset.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#03172025</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-03-17-2025-spaces</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[spaces]]></category>
            <pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Enhanced agent discovery with new search capabilities. Users can now search for agents by either ...]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Enhanced agent discovery with new search capabilities. Users can now search for agents by either agent slug or agent ID directly from both the agents list view and the agents detail page.</p>
<p>Optimized performance of the getAgents endpoint through pagination implementation. This significantly improving response times and scalability when working with large collections of agents.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#03072025</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-03-07-2025-dataxp</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[dataxp]]></category>
            <pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Records with readonly configurations are now handled differently in the]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Records with readonly configurations are now handled differently in the<br>
replaceRecords operation. A new option called excludeReadOnly has been<br>
introduced to control whether readonly records or fields should be skipped or<br>
replaced. If excludeReadOnly is set to true, records with a readonly config or<br>
fields marked as readonly will not be replaced during the replaceRecords<br>
operation. If excludeReadOnly is false or not provided, readonly records and<br>
fields will be replaced as before.</p>
<p>The findAndReplaceRecords method in the WorkbooksService now checks if the field<br>
being replaced is readonly and throws an error if excludeReadOnly is set to<br>
true, preventing modification of readonly fields.</p>
<p>Several new tests have been added to validate the behavior of the replaceRecords<br>
operation with readonly records and fields, covering scenarios with<br>
excludeReadOnly set to true and false.</p>
<p>The SearchRecordsOptions and GetCellValuesOptions interfaces have been updated<br>
to include the new excludeReadOnly option.</p>
<p>Example usage:</p>
<pre><code class="language-typescript">// Replace non-readonly records or fields
const records = await wb.op.replaceRecords({
  sheetId: wb.contacts.id,
  options: {},
  find: &quot;John&quot;,
  replace: &quot;Jonathan&quot;,
  field: { key: &quot;firstName&quot; },
  legacyReplace: false,
  actorId: UserId.make(),
});

// Skip readonly records or fields
const records = await wb.op.replaceRecords({
  sheetId: wb.contacts.id,
  options: { excludeReadOnly: true },
  find: &quot;John&quot;,
  replace: &quot;Jonathan&quot;,
  field: { key: &quot;firstName&quot; },
  legacyReplace: false,
  actorId: UserId.make(),
});
</code></pre>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#02042025</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-02-04-2025-dataxp</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[dataxp]]></category>
            <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2025 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Added language support for:]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Added language support for:</p>
<ul>
<li>Spanish (es-419)</li>
<li>Malay (ms)</li>
<li>Dutch (nl)</li>
<li>Polish (pl)</li>
<li>Swedish (sv)</li>
<li>Thai (th)</li>
<li>Chinese Traditional (zh-hant)</li>
<li>Chinese Traditional Hong Kong (zh-hant-HK)</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#01312025</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-01-31-2025-spaces</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[spaces]]></category>
            <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2025 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Namespace modification is now supported via API only. Other app fields remain]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Namespace modification is now supported via API only. Other app fields remain<br>
editable via the UI but the ability to edit a namespace has been removed<br>
post-creation.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#01302025</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-01-30-2025-dataxp</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[dataxp]]></category>
            <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2025 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fixes bug where long document titles would overlap the page header.]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Fixes bug where long document titles would overlap the page header.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#01302025</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-01-30-2025-spaces</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[spaces]]></category>
            <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2025 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The order of imports from the `@flatfile/api` module has been updated. The `RecordUpdates` and `S...]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>The order of imports from the <code>@flatfile/api</code> module has been updated. The <code>RecordUpdates</code> and <code>Success</code> types are now imported in a different order.</p>
<p>The implementation of the <code>clearColumn</code> method has been refactored. Instead of using the <code>map</code> and <code>filter</code> array methods, it now uses the <code>reduce</code> method to generate the <code>recordsUpdates</code> array. The new implementation checks if the field value exists and if the field is not read-only before clearing it. This change likely improves performance and readability.</p>
<p>The wording of the <code>info</code> and <code>outcome.message</code> properties in the <code>transitionJob</code> call has been updated from &quot;Column was removed&quot; to &quot;Column was cleared&quot;. This change provides more accurate messaging about the action performed.</p>
<p>Additionally, the code now handles read-only fields correctly. If a field is marked as read-only in the <code>RecordConfig</code>, its value will not be cleared.</p>
<p>These changes improve the functionality, performance, and messaging of the <code>clearColumn</code> logic without introducing any breaking changes to the external interface.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#01272025</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-01-27-2025-dataxp</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[dataxp]]></category>
            <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The unique validation and record/cell validity handling has been improved to:]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>The unique validation and record/cell validity handling has been improved to:</p>
<ul>
<li>properly escape field keys containing special characters like periods</li>
<li>correctly apply the <code>error</code> state and appropriate error messages when duplicate values are encountered for fields with a unique constraint</li>
<li>handle cases where all initially added records have invalid (duplicate) values for fields with a unique constraint</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#01242025</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-01-24-2025-dataxp</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[dataxp]]></category>
            <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[When clearing a column in a job operation, a snapshot of the sheet will be taken]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>When clearing a column in a job operation, a snapshot of the sheet will be taken<br>
before the column is cleared. This snapshot will be labeled with the specific<br>
column key that is being cleared, providing a record of the sheet state before<br>
the column clearing operation. The snapshot is taken by calling a new utility<br>
function <code>takeSnapshotForJob</code>, which handles creating and labeling the snapshot<br>
based on the job, sheet, and column details. This allows developers to review<br>
the sheet state prior to the column clearing if needed.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#01232025</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-01-23-2025-dataxp</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[dataxp]]></category>
            <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The release adds the ability to mark a space as an app template and filter]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>The release adds the ability to mark a space as an app template and filter<br>
spaces based on whether they are app templates or not.</p>
<p>This can be used with the new space-configure-from-template plugin to create new<br>
spaces using an existing space as a template.</p>
<p>When using Autobuild for a new App, the space generated during Autobuild will<br>
automatically be tagged as the template for that App.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#01222025</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-01-22-2025-dataxp</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[dataxp]]></category>
            <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[We added the ability to sort enum fields by label, value, or ordinal within the enum field config...]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>We added the ability to sort enum fields by label, value, or ordinal within the enum field config. This will ensure that enums will be displayed in the chosen order in mapping and review table. The default sortBy is label.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#01222025</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-01-22-2025-dataxp</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[dataxp]]></category>
            <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The release introduces the ability to filter spaces by the associated app ID]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>The release introduces the ability to filter spaces by the associated app ID<br>
when retrieving a list of spaces. A new query parameter <code>appId</code> has been added<br>
to the <code>/v1/spaces</code> endpoint. Developers can now pass the <code>appId</code> query<br>
parameter to retrieve only the spaces associated with the specified app. For<br>
example, <code>?appId=us_app_123</code> will return only spaces linked to the app with ID<br>
<code>us_app_123</code>. If an invalid or non-existent app ID is provided, an empty list<br>
will be returned.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#01222025</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-01-22-2025-dataxp</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[dataxp]]></category>
            <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[An error is now thrown if attempting to clear a readonly column in a sheet. This]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>An error is now thrown if attempting to clear a readonly column in a sheet. This<br>
prevents modifying data in readonly columns.</p>
<p>Example:</p>
<pre><code>const field = {
  key: 'ReadonlyColumn',
  label: 'Readonly Column',
  type: 'string',
  readonly: true
}
</code></pre>
<p>Attempting to clear this column will throw an error: 'Column is readonly and<br>
cannot be cleared'.</p>
<p>An error is also thrown if attempting to clear any column in a readonly sheet.<br>
This prevents modifying data in readonly sheets.</p>
<p>Example:</p>
<pre><code>const sheet = {
  config: {
    readonly: true,
    fields: [...]
  }
}
</code></pre>
<p>Attempting to clear a column in this sheet will throw an error: 'Sheet is<br>
readonly. Column cannot be cleared'.</p>
<p>These changes ensure data integrity by preventing unintended modification of<br>
readonly data.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#01172025</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-01-17-2025-dataxp</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[dataxp]]></category>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The `clearColumnAction` now has a constraint added that checks if the column is enabled before al...]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>The <code>clearColumnAction</code> now has a constraint added that checks if the column is enabled before allowing the action to be executed. This ensures that the action can only be performed on columns that are currently enabled, preventing any potential issues or errors that could arise from attempting to clear a disabled column.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#01132025</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-01-13-2025-dataxp</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[dataxp]]></category>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The manual entry and file upload button shown when the workbook is empty have]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>The manual entry and file upload button shown when the workbook is empty have<br>
has their max width updated so they can support more text.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#01062025</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-01-06-2025-spaces</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[spaces]]></category>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Trailing empty records in CSV files will now be trimmed during file extraction.]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Trailing empty records in CSV files will now be trimmed during file extraction.<br>
Empty records in-between records with values will continue to be kept.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#12302024</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-12-30-2024-dataxp</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[dataxp]]></category>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[- Record order is now maintained when inserting records]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Record order is now maintained when inserting records</li>
<li>When using the Flatfile API to add records, the order of those records will<br>
now be preserved keeping the original sequence as provided</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#12202024</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-12-20-2024-dataxp</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[dataxp]]></category>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fixes a bug where AI assist would crash when ‘config’ object or the ‘options’]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Fixes a bug where AI assist would crash when ‘config’ object or the ‘options’<br>
array is undefined.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#12102024</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-12-10-2024-spaces</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[spaces]]></category>
            <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fixes a bug where an error would be thrown when config options was undefined]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Fixes a bug where an error would be thrown when config options was undefined<br>
during sheet upsert operations.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#12092024</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-12-09-2024-dataxp</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[dataxp]]></category>
            <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[There was a bug causing the name of environment secrets not to update when]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>There was a bug causing the name of environment secrets not to update when<br>
edited. This fixes the bug ensuring environment secret names are updated.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#12062024</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-12-06-2024-dataxp</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[dataxp]]></category>
            <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The `viewMapped` functionality has been updated to include new text strings for]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>The <code>viewMapped</code> functionality has been updated to include new text strings for<br>
messaging related to updating a table to only view mapped fields. The messages<br>
include &quot;Updating the table to only view mapped fields&quot;, &quot;Halfway there, hang<br>
tight...&quot;, &quot;Almost done...&quot;, &quot;Table update complete. Please audit the data&quot;, and<br>
&quot;An error occurred while updating the workbook. See Event Logs.&quot; These strings<br>
will be displayed to the user during the process of updating a table to show<br>
only mapped fields, providing status updates and handling potential errors. This<br>
change enhances the user experience by providing clear communication during this<br>
operation.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#12042024</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-12-04-2024-spaces</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[spaces]]></category>
            <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A bug fix was made to the handling of enum field options when updating a sheet.]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>A bug fix was made to the handling of enum field options when updating a sheet.<br>
Previously, if the <code>config.options</code> property was undefined, an error would<br>
occur. Now, if <code>config.options</code> is undefined, it defaults to an empty array.<br>
This ensures that the code can safely handle cases where <code>config.options</code> is not<br>
present or is undefined. For example, if a developer was updating a sheet with<br>
an enum field that did not previously have any options defined, the update can<br>
now proceed without errors.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#12022024</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-12-02-2024-dataxp</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[dataxp]]></category>
            <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Added three keys: `addColumn`, `clearColumn`, and `removeColumn` with their]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Added three keys: <code>addColumn</code>, <code>clearColumn</code>, and <code>removeColumn</code> with their<br>
respective translations for adding, clearing, and removing columns.</p>
<p>In the English translation file, the title of the “mapValues” section has been<br>
updated from “Map values” to “Map Fields”.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#12022024</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-12-02-2024-spaces</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[spaces]]></category>
            <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Updates to the mapping flow to prevent a user from accidentally navigating]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Updates to the mapping flow to prevent a user from accidentally navigating<br>
&quot;back&quot; into a mapping flow after it has already been completed.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#11132024</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-11-13-2024-spaces</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[spaces]]></category>
            <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bug Fixes in Edit and Create App Forms]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Bug Fixes in Edit and Create App Forms</strong></p>
<p>We've resolved several issues affecting the Edit and Create App forms:</p>
<ul>
<li>Fixed form validation issues</li>
<li>Improved error handling</li>
<li>Enhanced user feedback</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#10282024</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-10-28-2024-dataxp</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[dataxp]]></category>
            <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2024 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Updated the AutoBuild flow to allow editing the working space name during the]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Updated the AutoBuild flow to allow editing the working space name during the<br>
build process. The name can now be edited by clicking an icon next to the space<br>
name, which reveals an input field to enter a new name. The name change is saved<br>
when the input field loses focus or the Enter key is pressed. Added a badge<br>
indicating &quot;Dev Mode&quot; when not in the production environment.</p>
<p>Simplified the loading step by removing the detailed progress indicators and<br>
showing only a centered loader component.</p>
<p>Updated the BlueprintTab component to display a bottom border and align the<br>
blueprint view action icons to the right.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#10172024</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-10-17-2024-dataxp</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[dataxp]]></category>
            <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Implemented sheet ordering functionality in the sidebar. Sheets are now]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Implemented sheet ordering functionality in the sidebar. Sheets are now<br>
displayed in the order specified by the <code>sheetSidebarOrder</code> setting in the<br>
workbook. Any sheets not included in the order are appended to the end.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#10032024</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-10-03-2024-spaces</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[spaces]]></category>
            <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2024 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The getDataDiff function has been updated to handle array values correctly when]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>The getDataDiff function has been updated to handle array values correctly when<br>
comparing proposed changes with existing source (src) and artifact data.</p>
<p>If the proposed array value is the same as the existing array value in either<br>
the source or artifacts, it will not be included in the changeset returned by<br>
getDataDiff.</p>
<p>The function now uses the lodash isEqual utility to compare array values,<br>
instead of strict equality (===), to account for differences in order or<br>
reference of array elements.</p>
<p>For example, if the proposed tags array is ['jedi', 'sith'], it will not be<br>
included in the changeset if the existing source tags are ['JEDI', 'SITH'] or if<br>
the existing artifact tags are ['jedi', 'sith'], because the values are<br>
considered equal despite differences in capitalization or array order.</p>
<p>This change ensures that unnecessary changes are not included in the changeset<br>
when working with array values, reducing noise and improving the accuracy of the<br>
changeset calculation.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#10012024</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-10-01-2024-dataxp</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[dataxp]]></category>
            <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[`@flatfile/api@1.9.17`]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><code>@flatfile/api@1.9.17</code></p>
<p>Secrets have been updated to introduce new optional fields for filtering.</p>
<p>A new optional <code>actorId</code> field of type <code>ActorId</code> has been added to the<br>
<code>ListSecrets</code> request type and <code>WriteSecret</code> type for secrets. This allows<br>
filtering secrets by the associated actor (user, guest, agent, or api key).</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#09272024</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-09-27-2024-dataxp</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[dataxp]]></category>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2024 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[`@flatfile/api@1.9.16`]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><code>@flatfile/api@1.9.16</code></p>
<p>Added new methods to for managing stored sheet constraints: <code>getConstraints</code>,<br>
<code>createConstraint</code>, <code>getConstraintById</code>, <code>updateConstraint</code>, and<br>
<code>deleteConstraint</code>.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#09252024</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-09-25-2024-dataxp</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[dataxp]]></category>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[`@flatfile/api@1.9.15`]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><code>@flatfile/api@1.9.15</code></p>
<p>With the addition of archived spaces there is now an ability to <code>unarchiveSpace</code><br>
method and <code>space:unarchived</code> event.</p>
<p>Deprecated use of metadata field at the cell value level, recommending use of<br>
record level metadata instead.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#09202024</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-09-20-2024-dataxp</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[dataxp]]></category>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2024 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[`spaces-ui`]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><code>spaces-ui</code></p>
<p>Updates to Snapshots resource to track changes to a sheet's schema (i.e. added<br>
and removed columns). A more robust Snapshot will enable more complex features<br>
when comparing 2 different snapshots.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#09112024</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-09-11-2024-spaces-ui</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[spaces-ui]]></category>
            <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Actions Resource]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><code>@flatfile/api@1.9.14</code></p>
<h4>Actions Resource</h4>
<p>Actions are now a first class resource. Developers may now create, retrieve,<br>
update, and delete actions via the api. New action events ActionCreated,<br>
ActionUpdated, and ActionDeleted are now being published and an actionId field<br>
has been added to the Context of events.</p>
<h4>Agent Versioning</h4>
<p>Agents versioning has been introduced. You may now retreieve agent versions via<br>
the api and revert to a previous version via the api and the dashboard.</p>
<h4>Token Refresh</h4>
<p>Guests actively using their space will have their token's automatically renewed.</p>
<h4>Sheet &amp; Cell Updates</h4>
<p>Support for array values in cell values has also been added.</p>
<h4>Job Metadata</h4>
<p>Metadta is now available on the <code>JobConfig</code> type, allowing additional data to be<br>
associated with jobs.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#09102024</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-09-10-2024-dataxp</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[dataxp]]></category>
            <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Session name validation has been introduced to the dashboard, preventing the]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Session name validation has been introduced to the dashboard, preventing the<br>
creation of new sessions with the same name.</p>
<p><img src="../changelog/images/spacename_validation.png" alt="image"></p>
<p>Note that sessions created via embedded or the api will not be constrained, this<br>
is a dashboard only validation.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#09062024</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-09-06-2024-dashboard</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[dashboard]]></category>
            <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[`@flatfile/api@1.9.13` `spaces-ui`]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><code>@flatfile/api@1.9.13</code> <code>spaces-ui</code></p>
<p>New fields 'guide' and 'guardrail' have been added to Actions. These options<br>
enable providing markdown guidance and warnings to your users.</p>
<pre><code class="language-typescript">actions: [
  {
    operation: 'submitActionFg',
    mode: 'foreground',
    label: 'Submit For Approval',
    type: 'string',
    description: 'Submit this data to a webhook.',
    primary: true,
    guide: {
        content: &quot;### Personalized Guide \n\n Before performing...&quot;
    },
    guardrail: {
        content: &quot;### Warning! \n\n This Submit ...&quot;
    }
  },
  {...}
],
</code></pre>
<p>The markdown content of guide will become accessible to the end user via a<br>
tooltip on the action element.</p>
<p>The <code>guardrail</code> component will render as a modal warning before the action event<br>
is triggered. This can be useful for actions that have critical consequences or<br>
require user acknowledgment before proceeding.</p>
<p>This can be useful for actions that have critical consequences or require user<br>
acknowledgment before proceeding.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#08202024</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-08-20-2024-spaces-ui</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[spaces-ui]]></category>
            <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2024 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[`spaces-ui`]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><code>spaces-ui</code></p>
<p>The &quot;requireAllValidTotal&quot; option has been added for custom actions in the Sheet<br>
toolbar. This new option requires all rows in the Sheet to be valid for the<br>
action to be enabled, regardless of selection. If &quot;requireAllValidTotal&quot; is set<br>
and there are any validation errors in the entire Sheet, the custom action will<br>
be disabled with the corresponding tooltip message.</p>
<p>The existing &quot;requireAllValid&quot; option has been updated to only apply to the<br>
selected rows, rather than all rows. If &quot;requireAllValid&quot; is set and there are<br>
validation errors in the selected rows, the custom action will be disabled with<br>
the corresponding tooltip message.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#08152024</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-08-15-2024-spaces-ui</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[spaces-ui]]></category>
            <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[`spaces-ui`]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><code>spaces-ui</code></p>
<p>Introduces support for handling locked sheets (indicated by the locked icon),<br>
and improves the handling of import files.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#08142024</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-08-14-2024-spaces-ui</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[spaces-ui]]></category>
            <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2024 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[`@flatfile/api@1.9.8`]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><code>@flatfile/api@1.9.8</code></p>
<p>A new <code>reference-list</code> property type has been added to allow defining an array<br>
of values referenced from another sheet. Links will be established automatically<br>
by the matching engine or similar upon an evaluation of unique or similar<br>
columns between datasets.</p>
<p>The <code>ReferencePropertyConfig</code> has been updated to make the <code>relationship</code><br>
property optional, allowing it to be omitted.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#08092024</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-08-09-2024-dataxp</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[dataxp]]></category>
            <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[`@flatfile/api@1.9.7`]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><code>@flatfile/api@1.9.7</code></p>
<p>New options have been added to the ListWorkbooksRequest to allow filtering<br>
workbooks by name, namespace, label, and treatment, as well as controlling<br>
whether to include sheets. For example, you can now pass a <code>name</code> parameter to<br>
filter workbooks by name, or a <code>treatment</code> parameter to filter by treatment. The<br>
<code>includeSheets</code> boolean parameter controls whether sheet data is included in the<br>
response.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#07232024</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-07-23-2024-dataxp</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[dataxp]]></category>
            <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2024 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[`@flatfile/api@1.9.6`]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><code>@flatfile/api@1.9.6</code></p>
<p>In AgentConfig type, a new optional property <code>sourceMap</code> of type string has been<br>
added. This allows including a source map for the agent code.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#07172024</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-07-17-2024-dataxp</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[dataxp]]></category>
            <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2024 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[`@flatfile/api@1.9.5`]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><code>@flatfile/api@1.9.5</code></p>
<p>A new property <code>treatments</code> of type <code>Flatfile.WorkbookTreatments[]</code> has been<br>
added to the <code>Workbook</code> and <code>CreateWorkbookConfig</code> types. This array allows<br>
specifying treatments for a workbook, with the currently available treatment<br>
being <code>ExtractedFromSource</code>. This change introduces a new external interface<br>
that developers using the package should be aware of when creating or updating<br>
workbooks.</p>
<p>Example usage:</p>
<pre><code class="language-typescript">import { Flatfile } from &quot;@flatfile/api&quot;;

const workbookConfig: Flatfile.CreateWorkbookConfig = {
  // ...other properties
  treatments: [Flatfile.WorkbookTreatments.ExtractedFromSource],
};
</code></pre>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#07162024</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-07-16-2024-dataxp</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[dataxp]]></category>
            <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[`@flatfile/api@1.9.3`]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><code>@flatfile/api@1.9.3</code></p>
<p>A new <code>JobOutcomeTrigger</code> type has been introduced to specify whether a job<br>
outcome's effect should be triggered automatically or manually.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#07132024</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-07-13-2024-dataxp</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[dataxp]]></category>
            <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2024 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Auto-Expanding Cell Input in Editor Component]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Auto-Expanding Cell Input in Editor Component</strong></p>
<p>We have enhanced the cell editing experience with an auto-expanding cell input<br>
that dynamically adjusts to fit the content. This improvement ensures that users<br>
can view and edit their data without constraints, enhancing the overall editing<br>
experience.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#06182024</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-06-18-2024-spaces</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[spaces]]></category>
            <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[`spaces-ui`]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><code>spaces-ui</code></p>
<p>Improvements have been made to error handling and user feedback in the file<br>
import and mapping process. If an error occurs, a popover is displayed to the<br>
user with the error message, providing clearer feedback on failures during the<br>
import process.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#06102024</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-06-10-2024-spaces-ui</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[spaces-ui]]></category>
            <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2024 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Select Header Row]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Select Header Row</strong></p>
<p>We've added a new feature that allows users to select the header row in the data<br>
preview. This feature is particularly useful when the first row of your data<br>
contains column headers, as it enables you to specify the header row for<br>
accurate data mapping.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#06072024</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-06-07-2024-dataxp</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[dataxp]]></category>
            <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2024 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Search for Users]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Search for Users</strong></p>
<p>You can now search for users in the manager users page. This feature allows you<br>
to quickly find users by name, email, or role, making it easier to manage your<br>
user base.</p>
<p><img src="../changelog/images/search.gif" alt="image"></p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#06072024</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-06-07-2024-dataxp</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[dataxp]]></category>
            <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2024 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Resend User Invite]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Resend User Invite</strong></p>
<p>There is now a <code>/users/:userId/resend-invite</code> endpoint enabling admins to resend<br>
an invitation to a user who has not yet accepted it.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#06062024</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-06-06-2024-dataxp</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[dataxp]]></category>
            <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bulk Deletion of Mapping Rules]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Bulk Deletion of Mapping Rules</strong></p>
<p>We added a method to delete multiple mapping rules from a program. This new<br>
<code>deleteMultipleRules</code> method simplifies the management of mapping rules by<br>
allowing bulk deletions. The <code>DeleteMultipleRulesRequest</code> type represents the<br>
request payload, detailing the array of rule IDs to be deleted.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#05302024</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-05-30-2024-dataxp</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[dataxp]]></category>
            <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Method to Delete Apps]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>New Method to Delete Apps</strong></p>
<p>We have introduced a new <code>delete</code> method that allows you to delete an app.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#05302024</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-05-30-2024-dataxp</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[dataxp]]></category>
            <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Enhanced Validation Messages for Records]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Enhanced Validation Messages for Records</strong></p>
<p>The <code>ValidationMessage</code> type has been enhanced with two new optional properties:<br>
<code>field</code> and <code>path</code>. The <code>field</code> property specifies which field the validation<br>
message pertains to, while the <code>path</code> property, of type <code>JsonPathString</code>,<br>
specifies the JSONPath for the validation message. These enhancements provide<br>
more context and precision in validation feedback.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#05302024</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-05-30-2024-spaces</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[spaces]]></category>
            <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Enhanced Job Outcomes with Custom Views]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Enhanced Job Outcomes with Custom Views</strong></p>
<p>The <code>JobOutcomeNext</code> type now includes a new <code>view</code> option, allowing jobs to<br>
specify a custom view that should be displayed upon completion. To support this,<br>
we introduced the <code>JobOutcomeNextView</code> type, which provides details for the<br>
custom view, including the sheet ID, hidden columns, and an optional label.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#05302024</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-05-30-2024-dataxp</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[dataxp]]></category>
            <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Method to Update Sheets]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>New Method to Update Sheets</strong></p>
<p>We introduced a new <code>updateSheet</code> method that allows you to update a sheet's<br>
name, slug, and metadata. The <code>SheetUpdateRequest</code> type represents the update<br>
request payload, including the name, slug, and metadata of the sheet.<br>
Additionally, an optional <code>metadata</code> property has been added to the <code>Sheet</code> and<br>
<code>SheetUpdate</code> types, allowing for the storage of contextual metadata related to<br>
the sheet.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#05302024</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-05-30-2024-dataxp</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[dataxp]]></category>
            <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[`spaces-ui`]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><code>spaces-ui</code></p>
<p>A new &quot;Update View&quot; button can now be found in the job outcome modal for jobs<br>
that modify the visibility of columns in a workbook sheet. This button triggers<br>
updating the column visibility based on the job outcome.</p>
<p>There are 2 new capabilities to the next property of Job Outcomes:</p>
<ul>
<li><code>view</code> gives developers the ability to manipulate the Sheet's view on<br>
completion of a Job - Giving control over things like applying a filter or<br>
hiding a column</li>
<li><code>download</code> gives developers the ability to include file details (such as a<br>
fileName and URL), which are then used to trigger a download to the user's<br>
browser on completion of the job</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#05292024</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-05-29-2024-spaces-ui</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[spaces-ui]]></category>
            <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Environment Lifecycle Events]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>New Environment Lifecycle Events</strong></p>
<p>We've added new domain <code>Environment</code> events expanding the scope of domains our<br>
system recognizes. To leverage these events, you can listen on to the following<br>
topics: The corresponding event topics are <code>environment:created</code>,<br>
<code>environment:updated</code>, and <code>environment:deleted</code>.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#05142024</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-05-14-2024-dataxp</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[dataxp]]></category>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2024 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Enhanced Job Configuration Descriptions]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Enhanced Job Configuration Descriptions</strong></p>
<p>We have added descriptions for the DeleteRecordsJobConfig properties to provide<br>
better clarity: An optional <code>filter</code> param allows allows you to provide options<br>
to filter records, with the default set to none while the <code>filterField</code> param<br>
enables narrowing the valid/error filter results to a specific field, but it<br>
requires the filter to be set.</p>
<p>We corrected a typo in the <code>JobOutcomeNextFiles</code> type by renaming the file<br>
property to files to accurately represent an array of file objects.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#05142024</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-05-14-2024-dataxp</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[dataxp]]></category>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2024 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Saving and Sharing Custom Views]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><code>spaces-ui</code></p>
<h4>Saving and Sharing Custom Views</h4>
<p>Users can now apply filters, sorting, and search queries to the Sheet data and<br>
save those settings as a reusable view. Key changes include:</p>
<ul>
<li>Added a &quot;Views&quot; dropdown in the Sheet toolbar to manage and apply saved views.</li>
<li>Added a &quot;Save View&quot; modal that allows users to name and save the current Sheet<br>
filters/sorting as a view.</li>
<li>Users can copy a sharable link with the view settings applied.</li>
<li>Saved views are grouped into &quot;My Views&quot; and &quot;All Views&quot; sections.</li>
<li>Added backend APIs to create, update, and delete saved views.</li>
<li>Added new React hooks and components to support the saved views functionality.</li>
<li>Updated translations for the new UI elements related to saved views.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#05072024</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-05-07-2024-spaces-ui</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[spaces-ui]]></category>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Updated `ListDocumentsResponse`]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Updated <code>ListDocumentsResponse</code></strong></p>
<p>The <code>data</code> property now returns an array of <code>Document</code> objects instead of the<br>
previous <code>DocumentResponse</code>. This change standardizes the format and improves<br>
consistency in how document data is handled.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#05032024</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-05-03-2024-dataxp</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[dataxp]]></category>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2024 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Enhanced Job Configuration]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Enhanced Job Configuration</strong></p>
<p>We added a new <code>predecessorIds</code> property to <code>JobConfig</code>. This property allows<br>
you to specify job dependencies, meaning you can list the IDs of jobs that must<br>
be completed before the current job can start. This helps in managing and<br>
sequencing job execution more effectively.</p>
<p>We added a new feature to handle job outcomes more effectively with a new type<br>
called <code>JobOutcomeNext</code> and its variant files. This includes:</p>
<ul>
<li><code>JobOutcomeNextFileObject</code> Stores individual file information with an ID and<br>
optional label.</li>
<li><code>JobOutcomeNextFiles</code> Handles multiple files, including an array of<br>
JobOutcomeNextFileObject instances and an optional label.</li>
</ul>
<p>We also added a waiting value to the JobStatus enum to indicate when a job is<br>
paused or pending, improving job processing workflows.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#05032024</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-05-03-2024-dataxp</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[dataxp]]></category>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2024 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Enhanced Views Request and Response]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Enhanced Views Request and Response</strong></p>
<p>We updated <code>ListViewsRequest</code> to include optional <code>pageSize</code> and <code>pageNumber</code><br>
properties, allowing for pagination when retrieving views. We've also added a<br>
<code>createdBy</code> property to <code>View</code> and <code>ViewResponse</code> to track the creator of each<br>
view.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#05032024</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-05-03-2024-spaces</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[spaces]]></category>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2024 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Improved event emission logic for workbook creation and update]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Improved event emission logic for workbook creation and update</strong></p>
<p>Previously, the <code>workbook:created</code> event was emitted even when the workbook was<br>
only being updated. Now, the logic emits a <code>workbook:updated</code> event when<br>
necessary. Additionally, the <code>POST /:workbookId/rebuild</code> endpoint now handles<br>
eventing properly.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#05012024</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-05-01-2024-spaces</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[spaces]]></category>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Enhanced Date Parsing Capabilities]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Enhanced Date Parsing Capabilities</strong></p>
<p><strong>Expanded Support for Date Formats</strong>:</p>
<p>We've broadened our parsing algorithms to accurately recognize and sort a wider<br>
variety of date formats. This update ensures that when users upload files<br>
containing date fields, the system robustly handles various international date<br>
formats and styles.</p>
<p><strong>Improved Sorting Accuracy</strong>:</p>
<p>Dates are now correctly sorted based on their actual chronological order,<br>
regardless of the format input. This enhancement reduces errors and<br>
inconsistencies previously encountered with date sorting, ensuring data<br>
integrity and reliability during file uploads.</p>
<p><strong>User Experience Improvement</strong>:</p>
<p>Users no longer need to modify or standardize date formats in their files before<br>
uploading. Flatfile automatically interprets and processes diverse date inputs,<br>
simplifying workflows and reducing manual data preprocessing.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#05012024</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-05-01-2024-spaces</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[spaces]]></category>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sorted Workbooks in Mapping]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Sorted Workbooks in Mapping</strong></p>
<p>Selecting a Sheet in the mapping flow has been updated to apply the same sort<br>
order consideration as the sidebar. This enhancement ensures consistency in<br>
workbook sorting for improved user navigation.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#04252024</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-04-25-2024-spaces</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[spaces]]></category>
            <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2024 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Origin info now exists in Files table]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Origin info now exists in Files table</strong></p>
<p>Now, origin tracking is available for file uploads, supporting sources like<br>
Google Drive, File System, Box, and OneDrive.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#04232024</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-04-23-2024-spaces</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[spaces]]></category>
            <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2024 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Improved Duplicate Field Key Validation in Workbook Sheets]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Improved Duplicate Field Key Validation in Workbook Sheets</strong></p>
<p><strong>Case-Insensitive Checking</strong>:</p>
<p>Our latest update enhances the validation process by identifying duplicate field<br>
keys in workbook sheets, including case-insensitive comparisons. This ensures<br>
that field keys are unique regardless of character casing, maintaining data<br>
integrity and consistency across your datasets.</p>
<p><strong>Data Integrity Assurance</strong>:</p>
<p>By preventing the entry of duplicate keys, even when differences are only in<br>
letter casing, we enhance the accuracy and reliability of data processing within<br>
our application.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#04222024</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-04-22-2024-spaces</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[spaces]]></category>
            <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[When uploading a file, you'll now see upload speeds in a user-friendly format]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>When uploading a file, you'll now see upload speeds in a user-friendly format<br>
(KB/s, MB/s, GB/s).</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#04222024</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-04-22-2024-spaces</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[spaces]]></category>
            <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Introducing customizable column sizes in the Flatfile Blueprint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Introducing customizable column sizes in the Flatfile Blueprint</strong></p>
<p>A new new sizing options has been added for string fields to enhance visual<br>
customization and user interface consistency.</p>
<p>See the new<br>
<a href="https://reference.flatfile.com/api-reference/workbooks/create#request.body.sheets.fields.string.appearance">property</a>.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#04182024</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-04-18-2024-spaces</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[spaces]]></category>
            <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Enhanced Workbook Build Process and Diagnostic Logging]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Enhanced Workbook Build Process and Diagnostic Logging</strong></p>
<p><strong>Extended Wait Time for Workbook Readiness</strong>:</p>
<p>To accommodate more complex data processing needs, we have extended the maximum<br>
wait time for workbook readiness from 30 to 120 seconds. This adjustment ensures<br>
that larger or more complex workbooks have sufficient time to complete their<br>
build process without interruption.</p>
<p><strong>Added Timeout Functionality</strong>:</p>
<p>We've introduced a new timeout feature that automatically stops the workbook<br>
building process if it exceeds the allotted time. This prevents prolonged waits<br>
and potential system overloads, improving overall system reliability.</p>
<p><strong>Improved Logging Capabilities</strong>:</p>
<p>To aid in troubleshooting and optimize workbook build performance, we have<br>
enhanced our logging system. Logs now include additional context information,<br>
offering deeper insights into the workbook building process and helping identify<br>
and resolve issues more efficiently.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#04172024</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-04-17-2024-spaces</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[spaces]]></category>
            <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2024 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Enhanced Cell-Level Control in Records]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Enhanced Cell-Level Control in Records</strong></p>
<p>We've introduced a new configuration property that allows users to set<br>
individual cells within a record to read-only. This enhancement extends our<br>
previous functionality where only entire columns or sheets could be designated<br>
as read-only. Now, you can apply more granular control over data manipulation by<br>
restricting editing at the cell level, improving data integrity and compliance.</p>
<p>See the<br>
<a href="https://reference.flatfile.com/api-reference/records/update#request.body.config.readonly">reference</a>.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#04122024</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-04-12-2024-spaces</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[spaces]]></category>
            <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Support continuing to the next row on enter key press]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Support continuing to the next row on enter key press</strong></p>
<p>Users can now seamlessly move to the next row in the cell by hitting the enter<br>
key. This enhancement improves the user experience and streamlines data entry in<br>
the Flatfile platform.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#04092024</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-04-09-2024-spaces</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[spaces]]></category>
            <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2024 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Multiline cell editing]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Multiline cell editing</strong></p>
<p>Users can now edit text in multi-line mode, enhancing the editing experience<br>
within the platform.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#04092024</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-04-09-2024-spaces</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[spaces]]></category>
            <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2024 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Introducing: Box Integration]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Introducing: Box Integration</strong></p>
<p>You can now upload a file from Box. Once you've connected your Box account, you<br>
can select a file to upload directly into Flatfile.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#03262024</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-03-26-2024-spaces</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[spaces]]></category>
            <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Introducing: Default Apps]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Introducing: Default Apps</strong></p>
<p>You can now set the default App for your Account. This App will be your default<br>
landing page. Additionally, any unlinked Spaces will appear here.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#03212024</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-03-21-2024-spaces</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[spaces]]></category>
            <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2024 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Refined AI Mapping Precision]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Refined AI Mapping Precision</strong></p>
<p>We’ve fine-tuned the interplay between AI-generated mapping suggestions and<br>
user-defined mapping history to enhance accuracy and user trust in our system.<br>
Previously, AI recommendations marked as “very confident” could override<br>
mappings with a user history score greater than 0.99. To address this, we’ve now<br>
implemented a cap on AI mapping scores, ensuring they do not exceed 0.99. This<br>
change guarantees that high-confidence user history takes precedence, fostering<br>
a more reliable and user-centric mapping experience.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#03172024</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-03-17-2024-spaces</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[spaces]]></category>
            <pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2024 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Streamlined User Invitation Process]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Streamlined User Invitation Process</strong></p>
<p>We've enhanced our user invitation system for improved clarity and data<br>
integrity. Each user can now hold only one active invitation at any given time.<br>
Any new invitation issued to a user will automatically replace the previous one.<br>
This measure is designed to maintain data accuracy and eliminate user confusion.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#03152024</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-03-15-2024-spaces</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[spaces]]></category>
            <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2024 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Intuitive Column Management in Real-Time]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Intuitive Column Management in Real-Time</strong></p>
<p>We've refined our column management experience to align with your expectations<br>
for immediate, responsive interactions. Key updates include:</p>
<p>Instant Feedback: Adjustments made within the column management panel now<br>
reflect instantly on the table. This immediate update ensures you can<br>
dynamically manage your view without waiting for panel closure.</p>
<p>Enhanced User Experience: This change addresses feedback regarding the previous<br>
UX, where updates only occurred post-panel closure, leading to confusion. Now,<br>
you can see the impact of your selections or deselections in real-time, making<br>
for a more intuitive and satisfying user experience.</p>
<p>These improvements are designed to make your data management processes more<br>
efficient and user-friendly, allowing for seamless adjustments to your viewing<br>
preferences on the fly.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#03132024</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-03-13-2024-spaces</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[spaces]]></category>
            <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Introducing `lastActivityAt` - Your Insight into Space Dynamics]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Introducing <code>lastActivityAt</code> - Your Insight into Space Dynamics</strong></p>
<p><code>lastActivityAt</code> is designed to provide you with comprehensive insights into the<br>
activity within your Spaces. Here's what you need to know:</p>
<p><strong>What is lastActivityAt?</strong></p>
<p>An optional datetime attribute that marks the date of the last significant<br>
activity within a Space. Activities considered include, but are not limited to,<br>
adding records to a sheet, uploading files, or altering the configuration of a<br>
workbook.</p>
<p><strong>Precision and Insight:</strong></p>
<p>Tracked with second-by-second-level precision, <code>lastActivityAt</code> offers a<br>
valuable overview of your Space's engagement and operational dynamics, helping<br>
you understand user behavior and space utilization better.</p>
<p>Reach out with feedback as we continue to enhance the utility of this feature to<br>
support your needs better.</p>
<p><a href="https://reference.flatfile.com/api-reference/spaces/get#response.body.data.lastActivityAt">Learn more</a></p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#03082024</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-03-08-2024-spaces</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[spaces]]></category>
            <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Resolved Document Auto-Update Issue]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Resolved Document Auto-Update Issue</strong></p>
<p>We fixed an issue where Documents weren't automatically updating in response to<br>
event stream activities (such as document creation, updates, or deletions). This<br>
fix ensures that document changes are now promptly reflected in the UI, keeping<br>
your Space synchronized with all recent activities.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#03072024</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-03-07-2024-spaces</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[spaces]]></category>
            <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Enhanced Metadata Management in `@flatfile/plugin-record-hook`]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Enhanced Metadata Management in <code>@flatfile/plugin-record-hook</code></strong></p>
<p>We've resolved a critical bug in the RecordHook functionality, where <code>metadata</code><br>
wasn't correctly assigned during record updates. By overhaulubg the workflow for<br>
setting and clearing metadata across various scenarios, we've can ensure<br>
accurate and consistent metadata management.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#03052024</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-03-05-2024-spaces</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[spaces]]></category>
            <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Introducing Email Theming for Pro Plan Customers]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Introducing Email Theming for Pro Plan Customers</strong></p>
<p>Users can now update their space metadata object with a theme configuration to<br>
customize the look of their emails. When this feature is flagged on, users can<br>
enjoy custom theming in their email communications.</p>
<pre><code class="language-js">{&quot;theme&quot;:
        {&quot;email&quot;:
        {&quot;logo&quot;:&quot;https://i.imgur.com/xuzxTAU.png&quot;,
        &quot;textColor&quot;:&quot;#FDEBF7&quot;,
        &quot;titleColor&quot;:&quot;#FFC0CB&quot;,
        &quot;buttonBgColor&quot;:&quot;#A7C7E7&quot;,
        &quot;backgroundColor&quot;:&quot;#34495E&quot;,
        &quot;buttonTextColor&quot;:&quot;#FFFFFF&quot;,
        &quot;footerTextColor&quot;:&quot;#F4D1D1&quot;}
        }
}
</code></pre>
<p>Learn more about <a href="../guides/theming.mdx">Theming</a>.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#02292024</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-02-29-2024-spaces</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[spaces]]></category>
            <pubDate>Thu, 29 Feb 2024 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Enhanced Enum Mapping Logic for Datasets with No Values]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Enhanced Enum Mapping Logic for Datasets with No Values</strong></p>
<p>We’ve addressed a nuanced issue concerning enum mapping and rule application in<br>
datasets with no values. Previously, the system saved enum mapping rules with a<br>
logic in place to reuse these rules if every value in a new dataset matched the<br>
rule. This approach inadvertently included scenarios where datasets had no<br>
values, considering them as matching all rules due to the absence of values.</p>
<p>Now, the system filters and applies enum mapping rules based solely on the<br>
values present in the new dataset. This change ensures that rules are applied<br>
more accurately, enhancing the system’s logic in handling datasets, especially<br>
those without any values. This update aims to provide a more reliable and<br>
logical framework for data processing and rule application.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#02292024</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-02-29-2024-spaces</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[spaces]]></category>
            <pubDate>Thu, 29 Feb 2024 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dashboard authentication now lasts 24 hours]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Dashboard authentication now lasts 24 hours</strong></p>
<p>Enjoy longer, uninterrupted sessions when working with your Flatfile Dashboard.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#02292024</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-02-29-2024-spaces</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[spaces]]></category>
            <pubDate>Thu, 29 Feb 2024 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Enhanced File Upload Experience: Multi-Selection and Drag-and-Drop Support]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Enhanced File Upload Experience: Multi-Selection and Drag-and-Drop Support</strong></p>
<p>We've upgraded the Files View with new capabilities to improve your file<br>
management workflow. Now, you can select and upload multiple files<br>
simultaneously through the File Uploader, streamlining the process.</p>
<p>While the upload progress is displayed for the initial file to maintain clarity,<br>
rest assured that all selected files are being uploaded.</p>
<p>Additionally, the drag-and-drop feature has been enhanced to support multiple<br>
files, making it easier than ever to upload documents directly into the Files<br>
View. This update is designed to enhance productivity and simplify your data<br>
management tasks.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#02292024</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-02-29-2024-spaces</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[spaces]]></category>
            <pubDate>Thu, 29 Feb 2024 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Optimized Space Loading Series: Reduced Requests for Translations]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Optimized Space Loading Series: Reduced Requests for Translations</strong></p>
<p>We've streamlined the loading process for Spaces by eliminating an unnecessary<br>
request for translations that previously triggered an additional getSpaceById<br>
call. This refinement reduces the load time, ensuring Spaces are displayed more<br>
promptly for a smoother user experience.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#02272024</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-02-27-2024-spaces</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[spaces]]></category>
            <pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Enhanced Filtering on `GET /spaces` Endpoint with Namespace Parameter
Support]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Enhanced Filtering on <code>GET /spaces</code> Endpoint with Namespace Parameter<br>
Support</strong></p>
<p>We've upgraded the <code>GET /spaces</code> endpoint to support an empty value for the<br>
<code>namespace</code> query parameter. This update allows for more nuanced filtering,<br>
specifically enabling the identification of spaces without a namespace. When the<br>
namespace parameter is omitted entirely, the endpoint now returns spaces across<br>
all namespaces, providing greater flexibility in data retrieval and management.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#02272024</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-02-27-2024-spaces</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[spaces]]></category>
            <pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Optimized Space Loading Performance Series: Deferring Blocking Requests]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Optimized Space Loading Performance Series: Deferring Blocking Requests</strong></p>
<p>By strategically eliminating or deferring five key blocking requests, we've<br>
streamlined the data fetching process. Key improvements include the removal of<br>
non-essential data fetches, optimizing the placement of the i18n context for<br>
more efficient rendering, and introducing a new utility for pre-processing date<br>
formats.</p>
<p>These updates collectively result in a smoother, faster user experience,<br>
reinforcing our commitment to efficiency and performance.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#02272024</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-02-27-2024-spaces</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[spaces]]></category>
            <pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Optimized Space Loading Series: Reduced Requests for Translations]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Optimized Space Loading Series: Reduced Requests for Translations</strong></p>
<p>We've streamlined the loading process for Spaces by eliminating an unnecessary<br>
request for translations that previously triggered an additional getSpaceById<br>
call. This refinement reduces the load time, ensuring Spaces are displayed more<br>
promptly for a smoother user experience.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#02232024</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-02-23-2024-spaces</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[spaces]]></category>
            <pubDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2024 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New: Advanced Column Filtering Feature]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>New: Advanced Column Filtering Feature</strong></p>
<p>Beyond the existing functionalities of sorting, replacing empty values, and<br>
conducting searches within fields, we’ve now integrated a precise value<br>
filtering option for columns. This new feature includes a convenient search<br>
mechanism to effortlessly pinpoint and filter by the specific value you’re<br>
seeking. Streamline your data analysis and management with this robust filtering<br>
capability.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#02232024</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-02-23-2024-spaces</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[spaces]]></category>
            <pubDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2024 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Enhanced Data Mapping Consistency with user created custom fields]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Enhanced Data Mapping Consistency with user created custom fields</strong></p>
<p>In our continuous efforts to streamline data import processes, we've implemented<br>
an improvement targeting the scenario where mapping rules from previous imports<br>
include destination fields no longer present in the current schema. This<br>
situation can arise if a custom field was added during a past import session and<br>
the data being imported is from a completely new sheet, often observed in<br>
embedded imports. With this update, we ensure a smoother data mapping experience<br>
by automatically filtering out rules that do not match the current destination<br>
blueprint, maintaining consistency and accuracy in your data integration<br>
efforts.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#02232024</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-02-23-2024-spaces</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[spaces]]></category>
            <pubDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2024 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Introducing the Flatfile Dedicated Mapping APIs]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Introducing the Flatfile Dedicated Mapping APIs</strong></p>
<p>We’re excited to announce the launch of the Flatfile Dedicated Mapping API, a<br>
significant enhancement to our suite of tools. This new API, encapsulated within<br>
a user-friendly Python library, is designed to fully harness Flatfile’s mapping<br>
capabilities. It provides a robust solution for mapping schemas directly within<br>
your systems, ensuring that your data remains secure in your database. This API<br>
is ideal for a range of applications, from data pipelines and API integrations<br>
to complex data conversion workflows.</p>
<p>The essence of mapping with this API is the transformation of source records<br>
into target records. This process ranges from straightforward tasks like<br>
renaming fields (for example, changing “first_name” to “firstName”) to more<br>
complex operations such as extracting substrings from fields or concatenating<br>
multiple fields.</p>
<p>Our Mapping API and accompanying Python library bring forth new opportunities<br>
for efficient and precise data mapping, offering customization to meet your<br>
unique needs and workflow requirements.</p>
<p>To get started, refer to the<br>
<a href="https://github.com/FlatFilers/flatfile-mapping">README</a>.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#01242024</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-01-24-2024-spaces</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[spaces]]></category>
            <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Expanding Global Reach with Additional Languages]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Expanding Global Reach with Additional Languages</strong></p>
<p>We've added an expansion of our language support to include a variety of new<br>
translations. This update builds upon our existing capabilities, which<br>
previously covered French, German, Indonesian, Portuguese, and Spanish.</p>
<p><strong>What's New?</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Italian (it)</li>
<li>Japanese (jp)</li>
<li>Korean (kr)</li>
<li>Brazilian Portuguese (pt-BR)</li>
<li>Turkish (tr)</li>
<li>Vietnamese (vi)</li>
<li>Chinese (zh)</li>
</ul>
<p>Our goal is to continuously add languages that resonate with our diverse user<br>
base. If there's a language you need that we haven't yet included, let us know!</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#01222024</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-01-22-2024-spaces</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[spaces]]></category>
            <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2024 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Feature Added: Disabling Actions for Empty Records in Workbook &
Sheet-Mounted Actions]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>New Feature Added: Disabling Actions for Empty Records in Workbook &amp;<br>
Sheet-Mounted Actions</strong></p>
<p>Developers can now add an optional flag to Actions, preventing users from<br>
initiating Actions when Sheets or Workbooks don’t yet have any records. This<br>
helps avoid unnecessary job failures and ensures Actions are performed only once<br>
data is present.</p>
<pre><code class="language-json">actions: [{
        &quot;constraints&quot;: [{ &quot;type&quot;: &quot;hasData&quot; }]
}]
</code></pre>
<p><a href="../orchestration/actions">Learn more</a> about all the constraints available for<br>
Sheet and Workbook Actions. or<br>
<a href="../guides/actions#workbook-and-sheet-mounted">See the Guide</a> to see it in use.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#01222024</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-01-22-2024-dataxp</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[dataxp]]></category>
            <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2024 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Introducing Composite Uniqueness for Enhanced Data Integrity]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Introducing Composite Uniqueness for Enhanced Data Integrity</strong></p>
<p>We’re delighted to introduce a new constraint in Sheets aimed at bolstering data<br>
integrity. This constraint guarantees that a designated combination of two or<br>
more fields maintains uniqueness throughout the entire Sheet.</p>
<p>To activate this feature, it’s as simple as adding certain parameters to the<br>
constraints property in your Sheet configuration.<br>
<a href="../blueprint/constraints#composite-uniqueness">See a breakdown</a> of the<br>
necessary parameters to effectively implement composite uniqueness.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#01222024</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-01-22-2024-dataxp</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[dataxp]]></category>
            <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2024 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Powered by Flatfile looks a little different now]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Powered by Flatfile looks a little different now</strong></p>
<p><img src="../changelog/images/powered_by.png" alt="image"></p>
<p>Based on user feedback, we've updated the visual design of the &quot;Powered by<br>
Flatfile&quot; chip to distinguish it from actionable buttons, enhancing the user<br>
interface for clarity.</p>
<p><Note><br>
For those interested in a fully branded experience, we offer the option to<br>
remove this chip entirely through our <a href="https://flatfile.com/pricing/">Professional<br>
package</a>.<br>
</Note></p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#01182024</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-01-18-2024-theming</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[theming]]></category>
            <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2024 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Improvements for `trackChanges` functionality]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Improvements for <code>trackChanges</code> functionality</strong></p>
<p>For users utilizing the <code>trackChanges</code> on their Workbooks (disables your actions<br>
until all commits are complete), we’ve addressed a critical workflow concern.</p>
<p>Changes in a Reference field result in the creation of a new commit event, which<br>
was leaving the original commit incomplete. Furthermore, this new commit wasn’t<br>
triggering an event emission, leading to a chain of incomplete commits.</p>
<p>We’ve refined the commit completion process: now, commits will be marked as<br>
complete whenever the user explicitly references a commit in an update request.</p>
<p>This adjustment is handled out of the box with <code>@flatfile/plugin-record-hook</code><br>
and ensures a more streamlined and reliable change tracking experience.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#01182024</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-01-18-2024-dataxp</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[dataxp]]></category>
            <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2024 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New: At-a-glance Insights are now available in the Sidebar]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>New: At-a-glance Insights are now available in the Sidebar</strong></p>
<p><img src="../changelog/images/sidebar-counts.gif" alt="image"></p>
<p>Enhancements to the Spaces sidebar now offer at-a-glance insights for greater<br>
efficiency: each workbook's entry displays a count of contained Sheets,<br>
alongside a tally of records within each Sheet. Additionally, the validity of<br>
records is intuitively indicated with color-coded dots—green for valid and red<br>
for invalid—directly within the Sheet summary. This allows for quick<br>
identification and management of data accuracy.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#01172024</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-01-17-2024-spaces</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[spaces]]></category>
            <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[We've optimized the file deletion process for large files. The next time you]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1></h1>
<p>We've optimized the file deletion process for large files. The next time you<br>
remove a sizable file, expect to experience a noticeably faster removal speed.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#01172024</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-01-17-2024-dataxp</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[dataxp]]></category>
            <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Toolbar blocking jobs Extended to Workbook-Mounted Actions]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Toolbar blocking jobs Extended to Workbook-Mounted Actions</strong></p>
<p>We've extended the functionality of the <code>toolbarBlocking</code> job mode beyond<br>
individual Sheets. Now, when it's applied to Workbook-mounted actions, this mode<br>
also disables workbook actions (including all of the Sheets actions/toolbars)<br>
during a job's progress. By its nature, it also still allows interaction with<br>
the actual data tables.</p>
<p>This enhancement provides more consistent control throughout your entire<br>
Workbook, ensuring tasks are completed efficiently and without accidental<br>
interference or unintended navigation.</p>
<p><a href="../orchestration/actions#optional-parameters">Learn more</a></p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#01122024</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-01-12-2024-dataxp</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[dataxp]]></category>
            <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2024 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[State-Based Messaging on Actions via Tooltips]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>State-Based Messaging on Actions via Tooltips</strong></p>
<p>We've introduced an exciting new capability to enhance user interaction and<br>
feedback in our application. You can now add custom messages to actions,<br>
tailored according to their state:</p>
<ul>
<li>Error</li>
<li>Info</li>
</ul>
<p>These messages will be displayed as tooltips when users hover over an action,<br>
providing context-specific text that corresponds to the action's current state.</p>
<p><a href="../guides/actions#usage-7">Follow the guide</a></p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#01122024</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-01-12-2024-dataxp</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[dataxp]]></category>
            <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2024 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Decoupling Actions Updates from the Workbook's Schema]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Decoupling Actions Updates from the Workbook's Schema</strong></p>
<p>Previously, using workbook update endpoint necessitated submitting all the<br>
fields, even for minor adjustments to an action. Now, with our improved <code>PATCH</code><br>
endpoint, you can update actions without needing to include the <code>fields</code><br>
property in your payload.</p>
<p>This refinement simplifies the update process, focusing solely on the changes<br>
you intend to make.</p>
<p><a href="https://reference.flatfile.com/api-reference/workbooks/update-a-workbook">See the endpoint</a></p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#01122024</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-01-12-2024-dataxp</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[dataxp]]></category>
            <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2024 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Previously, users experienced difficulties in adjusting column sizes correctly]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Previously, users experienced difficulties in adjusting column sizes correctly<br>
when other columns were either hidden or pinned. This fix ensures seamless and<br>
accurate resizing of columns, regardless of the visibility or status of adjacent<br>
columns, enhancing the overall usability and functionality of the data table.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#01122024</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-01-12-2024-dataxp</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[dataxp]]></category>
            <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2024 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Enhanced Visibility with Status Updates During File Extraction]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Enhanced Visibility with Status Updates During File Extraction</strong></p>
<p><img src="../changelog/images/extract-status.gif" alt="image"></p>
<p>A Toast now displays intermediate states to keep you informed every step of the<br>
way during file extraction.</p>
<p>When uploading a file directly to the table, you’ll see statuses like “Waiting<br>
for Extraction”, “Extracting”, and “Unsupported File”, along with detailed<br>
information about the outcome of extraction jobs.</p>
<p>When uploading on the Files page, the error message is toned down to an info<br>
message, as uploading files without an extractor is a legitimate scenario.</p>
<p>These updates are aimed at enhancing transparency and efficiency, ensuring<br>
you’re well-informed throughout the file extraction process.</p>
<p><a href="https://flatfile.com/plugins/category/extractors/">See extractor plugins</a></p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#01032024</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-01-03-2024-dataxp</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[dataxp]]></category>
            <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Improved Search Functionality for Null Values in GET Records Endpoint]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Improved Search Functionality for Null Values in GET Records Endpoint</strong></p>
<p>We've refined the search mechanism for empty cells in the GET records endpoint.<br>
In the past, users would specify <code>null</code> in the <code>searchValue</code> parameter to locate<br>
empty cells. However, this method posed ambiguity as it didn't clearly<br>
distinguish between an exact search for null values and a partial search for the<br>
string &quot;null&quot;.</p>
<p>Now, to accurately search for cells with null values, you should use empty<br>
double quotes <code>&quot;&quot;</code> in the <code>searchValue</code> parameter.</p>
<p><a href="https://reference.flatfile.com/api-reference/records/get-records">See the endpoint</a></p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#01032024</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-01-03-2024-dataxp</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[dataxp]]></category>
            <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Enhanced Theming Tabs, Tooltips, and Popovers]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Enhanced Theming Tabs, Tooltips, and Popovers</strong></p>
<p>We're excited to announce a broad range of new theming capabilities that enhance<br>
the visual appeal and customization of our platform:</p>
<p><strong>Usage</strong></p>
<pre><code class="language-jsx">{
  &quot;theme&quot;: {
    &quot;root&quot;: {
      &quot;borderColor&quot;: &quot;pink&quot;,
      &quot;modalBorderRadius&quot;: &quot;10px&quot;,
      &quot;popoverBorderRadius&quot;: &quot;8px&quot;,
      &quot;tabstripActiveColor&quot;: &quot;deepskyblue&quot;,
      &quot;tabstripInactiveColor&quot;: &quot;orange&quot;,
      &quot;popoverBackgroundColor&quot;: &quot;limegreen&quot;,
      &quot;tabstripHoverTextColor&quot;: &quot;gold&quot;,
      &quot;tooltipBackgroundColor&quot;: &quot;hotpink&quot;,
      &quot;tabstripHoverBorderColor&quot;: &quot;purple&quot;
    }
  }
}
</code></pre>
<ol>
<li><p>Theming for Tabs: Customize the look and feel of tabs to better match your<br>
application's design and user experience.</p></li>
<li><p>Enhanced Tooltip Styling: Gain more control over tooltip aesthetics with<br>
expanded theming options, ensuring they align seamlessly with your interface.</p></li>
<li><p>Refined Borders Across Components: Apply custom themes to borders, providing<br>
a sharper and more cohesive visual distinction for various elements.</p></li>
<li><p>Popover Customization: Tailor the appearance of popovers with new theming<br>
capabilities, enhancing their integration within your application's layout.</p></li>
<li><p>Modal Window Styling: Elevate the design of modal windows with customizable<br>
theming options, contributing to a more engaging and harmonious user<br>
experience.</p></li>
</ol>
<p>These updates offer a greater degree of flexibility in customizing the<br>
appearance of key UI components, allowing for a more integrated and visually<br>
consistent application design.</p>
<p><a href="../guides/theming">Learn more</a>.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#12212023</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-12-21-2023-theming</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[theming]]></category>
            <pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2023 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Field Descriptions now have Markdown Support]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Field Descriptions now have Markdown Support</strong></p>
<p><img src="../changelog/images/tooltips-with-markdown.gif" alt="image"></p>
<p>We're delighted to announce that field descriptions now support Markdown<br>
formatting. This enhancement enables you to create more informative and engaging<br>
field descriptions, complete with formatted text and hyperlinks.</p>
<p><strong>Usage</strong></p>
<pre><code class="language-jsx">&quot;fields&quot;: [
  {
    &quot;key&quot;: &quot;code&quot;,
    &quot;label&quot;: &quot;Product Code&quot;,
    &quot;description&quot;: &quot;This can be **markdown**.&quot;
    &quot;type&quot;: &quot;string&quot;
  },
]
</code></pre>
<ul>
<li><p>Rich Formatting Capabilities: Leverage the power of Markdown to format your<br>
field descriptions, making them more readable and useful.</p></li>
<li><p>Incorporate Links: Easily include links in your field descriptions, providing<br>
direct access to additional resources or related information.</p></li>
<li><p>Versatile Display Across Interfaces: These enriched descriptions are displayed<br>
as tooltips within the data table and in mapping. Additionally, the full text<br>
of the descriptions is available in the data checklist for comprehensive<br>
insights.</p></li>
</ul>
<p>This update is designed to improve the clarity and effectiveness of field<br>
descriptions, enhancing the overall user experience in data interaction and<br>
comprehension.</p>
<p>Learn more about <a href="../blueprint">Blueprint</a> and Fields.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#12152023</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-12-15-2023-dataxp</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[dataxp]]></category>
            <pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2023 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Default Value Added to `inputForm` fields]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Default Value Added to <code>inputForm</code> fields</strong></p>
<p>We've enhanced the <code>inputForm</code> feature in Actions by supporting <code>defaultValue</code><br>
settings for enums, strings, and textarea field types.</p>
<p><strong>Usage</strong></p>
<pre><code class="language-jsx">&quot;inputForm&quot;: {
  &quot;type&quot;: 'simple',
  &quot;fields&quot;: [
    {
      &quot;key&quot;: 'planName',
      &quot;label&quot;: 'Plan Name',
      &quot;type&quot;: 'string',
      &quot;description&quot;: 'The name of the plan',
      &quot;defaultValue&quot;: 'Default plan'
    },
  ]
}
</code></pre>
<p>This update allows for more intuitive and efficient data entry, as default<br>
values can be pre-filled in these fields, streamlining the user experience.</p>
<p>Learn more about <a href="../orchestration/actions#inputForm">Actions and Input Forms</a>.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#12152023</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-12-15-2023-dataxp</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[dataxp]]></category>
            <pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2023 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Enhanced Theming Interactive options]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Enhanced Theming Interactive options</strong></p>
<p><img src="../changelog/images/theming_dropdowns.png" alt="image"></p>
<p>The latest updates in our theming capabilities bring a fresh look and enhanced<br>
customization to various UI elements:</p>
<p><strong>Usage</strong></p>
<pre><code class="language-jsx">{
  &quot;theme&quot;: {
    &quot;root&quot;: {
      &quot;badgeBorderColor&quot;: &quot;green&quot;,
      &quot;interactiveBorderColor&quot;: &quot;orange&quot;,
      &quot;interactiveBorderRadius&quot;: &quot;0px&quot;
    },
    &quot;table&quot;: {
      &quot;cell&quot;: {
        &quot;active&quot;: {
          &quot;borderWidth&quot;: &quot;2px&quot;,
          &quot;boxShadow&quot;: &quot;3px 3px 0px 0px #000000&quot;
        }
      },
      &quot;tooltip&quot;: {
        &quot;borderRadius&quot;: &quot;0px&quot;
      },
      &quot;lookupEditor&quot;: {
        &quot;option&quot;: {
          &quot;borderRadius&quot;: {
            &quot;hover&quot;: &quot;0px&quot;,
            &quot;active&quot;: &quot;8px&quot;
          },
          &quot;backgroundColor&quot;: {
            &quot;hover&quot;: &quot;yellow&quot;,
            &quot;active&quot;: &quot;lavender&quot;
          }
        }
      }
    }
  }
}
</code></pre>
<ol>
<li><p>Enhanced Dropdown, Text Input, and Context Menu Theming: Users can now apply<br>
customized themes to dropdowns, text inputs, and context menus, offering a<br>
more cohesive and personalized interface design.</p></li>
<li><p>Refined Active Cell Styling in Tables: The active cell in the table now<br>
features themable border width and box shadow, adding depth and focus to the<br>
selected cell.</p></li>
<li><p>Upgraded Tooltips in Tables: Tooltips in the table now support theming for<br>
border radius and box shadow, allowing for smoother integration with the<br>
overall design aesthetic.</p></li>
<li><p>New Optional Border for Badges: An optional border can now be added to badges<br>
within the app. This update extends to TT badges in enum columns, providing a<br>
consistent and visually appealing element across the platform.</p></li>
</ol>
<p>These theming enhancements are part of our ongoing commitment to provide a<br>
versatile and visually engaging user experience, allowing for greater<br>
consistency and branding alignment across our platform.</p>
<p><a href="../guides/theming">Learn more</a>.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#12152023</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-12-15-2023-theming</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[theming]]></category>
            <pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2023 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Enhanced Theming options for Checkboxes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Enhanced Theming options for Checkboxes</strong></p>
<p><img src="../changelog/images/theming_checkboxes.png" alt="image"></p>
<p>We're pleased to announce the expansion of our theming capabilities with new<br>
customization options for checkboxes:</p>
<p><strong>Usage</strong></p>
<pre><code class="language-jsx">{
  &quot;theme&quot;: {
    &quot;root&quot;: {
      &quot;checkboxBorderRadius&quot;: &quot;0px&quot;,
      &quot;checkboxBorderColor&quot;: &quot;red&quot;
    },
    &quot;table&quot;: {
      &quot;inputs&quot;: {
        &quot;checkbox&quot;: {
          &quot;borderColor&quot;: &quot;magenta&quot;
        }
      }
    }
  }
}
</code></pre>
<ol>
<li><p>Customizable Checkbox Border Radius: Users now have the flexibility to theme<br>
the border radius of checkboxes, allowing for a more personalized and<br>
visually cohesive interface.</p></li>
<li><p>Theming for Checkbox Border Color: Alongside border radius customization,<br>
users can also theme the border color of checkboxes, adding another layer of<br>
visual customization to match your application's aesthetic.</p></li>
<li><p>Override Options in Table View: In table contexts, users have the added<br>
ability to override the default checkbox border color, offering even more<br>
control over the table's appearance and consistency with your overall design<br>
theme.</p></li>
</ol>
<p>These enhancements aim to provide greater flexibility and control over the UI,<br>
enabling users to tailor the look and feel of checkboxes to better align with<br>
their unique branding and design preferences.</p>
<p><a href="../guides/theming">Learn more</a>.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#12142023</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-12-14-2023-theming</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[theming]]></category>
            <pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2023 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Enhanced Theming options for Badges+]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Enhanced Theming options for Badges+</strong></p>
<p><img src="../changelog/images/theming_badges.png" alt="image"></p>
<p>We're excited to announce new additions to our theming capabilities, allowing<br>
for even more customization and a refined user experience.</p>
<p><strong>Usage</strong></p>
<pre><code class="language-jsx">&quot;theme&quot;: {
  &quot;root&quot;: {
    &quot;pillBorderRadius&quot;: &quot;0px&quot;,
    &quot;badgeBorderRadius&quot;:&quot;10em&quot;
  },
  &quot;table&quot;: {
    &quot;buttons&quot;: {
      &quot;pill&quot;: {
        &quot;color&quot;: &quot;white&quot;,
        &quot;backgroundColor&quot;: &quot;magenta&quot;
      },
      &quot;iconColor&quot;: &quot;magenta&quot;
    }
  }
}
</code></pre>
<p><strong>What's New:</strong></p>
<ol>
<li><p>Pill and Badge Border Radius Customization: You can now tailor the border<br>
radius of pills and badges within space theming. This update enables you to<br>
define and apply a consistent look across all pills and badges in the space<br>
according to your design preferences.</p></li>
<li><p>Toolbar Button Color Theming: We've also introduced the option to customize<br>
the color of toolbar buttons, giving you more control over the visual style<br>
of your toolbar.</p></li>
<li><p>Inherited and Customizable Toolbar Filters: Toolbar filters will<br>
automatically inherit the pill border radius settings for a unified<br>
appearance. However, this can be overridden to suit specific design needs,<br>
offering both convenience and flexibility.</p></li>
</ol>
<p>These enhancements are part of our ongoing commitment to providing a versatile<br>
and user-friendly platform that caters to your unique theming requirements.</p>
<p><a href="../guides/theming">Learn more</a>.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#12082023</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-12-08-2023-theming</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[theming]]></category>
            <pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Revamped UI for Foreground Jobs]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Revamped UI for Foreground Jobs</strong></p>
<p><img src="../changelog/images/foreground_facelift.png" alt="image"></p>
<p>We've given our foreground jobs a fresh, new look:</p>
<ol>
<li>Enhanced Job Modal Header: The job modal header now prominently displays job<br>
information, making it instantly visible and accessible.</li>
<li>Refined Display Details: Information that was previously in the header is now<br>
elegantly presented as an ultralight subline for improved readability.</li>
<li>Optimized Layout: We've repositioned the display of the percentage and<br>
remaining time for better clarity and focus.</li>
<li>Improved Time Estimation: For estimated completion time, we've introduced a<br>
fallback mechanism based on simple linear extrapolation, ensuring more<br>
accurate and reliable predictions.</li>
</ol>
<p>These updates are designed to offer a more intuitive and streamlined user<br>
experience in tracking and managing foreground jobs.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#12012023</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-12-01-2023-dataxp</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[dataxp]]></category>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Next Action Links in Job Outcome Dialogs Now Support Linking to internal
resources]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Next Action Links in Job Outcome Dialogs Now Support Linking to internal<br>
resources</strong></p>
<p><img src="../changelog/images/next_link.png" alt="image"></p>
<p>In addition to the existing ability to link to external URLs and trigger<br>
downloads, you can now also display links to internal resources upon job<br>
completion. This enhancement broadens the scope of actions you can perform,<br>
offering more versatility in directing users to relevant resources or actions<br>
post-job completion.</p>
<p>In this code below, we will create a button that says “See all downloads” with<br>
this path: <code>/space/us_sp_1234/files?mode=export</code></p>
<p><strong>Usage</strong></p>
<pre><code class="language-jsx listener">await api.jobs.complete(jobId, {
  outcome: {
    message: `The file has been created`,
    acknowledge: true,
    //Reference: https://platform.flatfile.com/s/space/{$id}/{path}?{$query}
    next: {
      type: &quot;id&quot;,
      id: &quot;dev_sp_1234&quot;,
      path: &quot;files&quot;,
      query: &quot;mode=export&quot;,
      label: &quot;See all downloads&quot;,
    },
  },
});
</code></pre>
<p>This improvement adds versatility and flexibility to your job outcomes,<br>
enhancing user interaction and experience.</p>
<p><a href="../orchestration/jobs#next-links">Learn more</a>.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#12012023</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-12-01-2023-dataxp</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[dataxp]]></category>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Next Action Links in Job Outcome Dialogs Now Support Retrying]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Next Action Links in Job Outcome Dialogs Now Support Retrying</strong></p>
<p>You can now also display links to retry a job upon job completion or failure.<br>
This enhancement broadens the scope of actions you can perform, offering more<br>
versatility in directing users to relevant resources or actions post-job<br>
completion.</p>
<p><strong>Usage</strong></p>
<pre><code class="language-jsx listener">await api.jobs.complete(jobId, {
  outcome: {
    message: `The file has been created`,
    acknowledge: true,
    next: {
      type: &quot;retry&quot;,
      label: &quot;Try again&quot;,
    },
  },
});
</code></pre>
<p>This improvement adds versatility and flexibility to your job outcomes,<br>
enhancing user interaction and experience.</p>
<p><a href="../orchestration/jobs#next-links">Learn more</a>.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#12012023</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-12-01-2023-dataxp</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[dataxp]]></category>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Enhanced Theming options for Filters]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Enhanced Theming options for Filters</strong></p>
<p><img src="../changelog/images/theming_chips.png" alt="image"></p>
<p>We've expanded the theming capabilities for filters, providing a more<br>
customizable and visually appealing interface:</p>
<p><strong>Usage</strong></p>
<pre><code class="language-jsx">&quot;theme&quot;: {
    &quot;table&quot;: {
      &quot;filters&quot;: {
        &quot;outerBorder&quot;: &quot;2px red solid&quot;,
        &quot;innerBorderRadius&quot;: &quot;0px&quot;,
        &quot;outerBorderRadius&quot;: &quot;0px&quot;
      }
  }
}
</code></pre>
<ol>
<li><p>New Styling Features for Filters: We've introduced the option to customize<br>
filters with borders and border radius as part of the table theme.</p></li>
<li><p>Flexible Border Radius Design: To accommodate the varying sizes of elements<br>
and the potential difference in calculated border radius, we now use both<br>
inner and outer border radius settings. This enhancement not only ensures a<br>
cohesive look but also adds an extra layer of styling flexibility to the<br>
filters.</p></li>
</ol>
<p>These improvements are designed to offer more control over the aesthetics of<br>
filters, enabling a seamless and integrated visual experience.</p>
<p><a href="../guides/theming">Learn more</a>.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#12012023</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-12-01-2023-theming</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[theming]]></category>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Introducing New Endpoint for Workbook Commit Retrieval]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Introducing New Endpoint for Workbook Commit Retrieval</strong></p>
<p>We're excited to announce the addition of the new GET<br>
<code>/workbooks/{workbookId}/commits</code> endpoint. This improvement streamlines the<br>
process of retrieving all commits associated with a specific workbook, offering<br>
a more efficient way to determine the completion status of all processing<br>
activities on that workbook.</p>
<p>While this enhancement primarily benefits the Flatfile UI, the endpoint is fully<br>
exposed, making it a valuable tool for developers looking to optimize commit<br>
retrieval and processing status checks in their own applications.</p>
<p><a href="https://reference.flatfile.com/api-reference/workbooks/get-commits-for-a-workbook">See the endpoint</a></p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#11282023</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-11-28-2023-dataxp</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[dataxp]]></category>
            <pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2023 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[We've successfully addressed and fixed the issue related to extracting/uploading]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>We've successfully addressed and fixed the issue related to extracting/uploading<br>
files with special characters in their names. If you previously encountered<br>
difficulties with such files, this update resolves those challenges, ensuring<br>
smoother and more reliable file handling going forward.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#11282023</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-11-28-2023-dataxp</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[dataxp]]></category>
            <pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2023 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Improved Handling of Long-Running Jobs with New Timeout Feature]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Improved Handling of Long-Running Jobs with New Timeout Feature</strong></p>
<p><img src="../changelog/images/job_failure.png" alt="image"></p>
<p>To enhance clarity and efficiency in job processing, we’ve implemented an update<br>
for managing long-running jobs. Previously, jobs that weren’t acknowledged<br>
within 5 minutes would silently fail due to a timeout by the agent, leading to<br>
confusion as these jobs never reached completion (They were left in an executing<br>
state).</p>
<p>To address this, we’ve now added a routine check that occurs every 5 minutes.<br>
This check will automatically fail jobs that are still executing but haven’t<br>
been<br>
<a href="https://reference.flatfile.com/api-reference/jobs/acknowledge-a-job">acknowledged</a><br>
(ack’d) within this timeframe. This update ensures better transparency and<br>
control in the job execution process, reducing confusion and streamlining<br>
operations.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#11282023</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-11-28-2023-dataxp</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[dataxp]]></category>
            <pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2023 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[You can now disable Actions when there are invalid records]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>You can now disable Actions when there are invalid records</strong></p>
<p><img src="../changelog/images/hasAllValid.gif" alt="image"></p>
<p>Previously, developers faced challenges in determining when all rows were valid,<br>
essential for preventing unintended data egress.</p>
<p>Now, developers can now add an optional flag to Actions, preventing users from<br>
initiating Actions when Sheets or Workbooks contain invalid records.</p>
<pre><code class="language-jsx">actions: [{
  ...
  constraints: [{ type: 'hasAllValid' }]
  ...
}]
</code></pre>
<p>Add a <code>constraints</code> parameter in your Action that includes <code>type: hasAllValid,</code><br>
to disable actions when there are invalid records.</p>
<p><a href="../guides/actions#usage">Learn more</a></p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#11202023</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-11-20-2023-dataxp</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[dataxp]]></category>
            <pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2023 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[We made an enhancement to bulk cell pasting. Previously, locking the cell]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>We made an enhancement to bulk cell pasting. Previously, locking the cell<br>
occurred prematurely, causing values to flash after pasting. Now, locking is<br>
effectively executed later, resulting in a smoother and more stable pasting<br>
experience.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#11202023</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-11-20-2023-spaces</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[spaces]]></category>
            <pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2023 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Space ID Search is now available in the Spaces Table]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Space ID Search is now available in the Spaces Table</strong></p>
<p><img src="../changelog/images/search_spaces.gif" alt="image"></p>
<p>We've added a new feature that allows you to search for spaces using their Space<br>
ID in the Spaces table. This enhancement simplifies the process of locating<br>
specific spaces quickly and efficiently.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#11202023</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-11-20-2023-spaces</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[spaces]]></category>
            <pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2023 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Enhanced Weighting Mechanism for User History in Enum Mapping]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Enhanced Weighting Mechanism for User History in Enum Mapping</strong></p>
<p>We assign an 80% value to other users' history compared to the current user's<br>
history. Previously, this was only applied to field mapping, Now, this approach<br>
has been extended to enum mapping as well.</p>
<p>This update addresses an issue where conflicting histories between two users<br>
could result in one user being unable to edit due to the other's history taking<br>
precedence.</p>
<p>With this enhancement, the system now more effectively balances historical<br>
inputs from different users, ensuring smoother and more equitable enum mapping<br>
automation.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#11172023</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-11-17-2023-files</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[files]]></category>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2023 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[_It's the little things_: Bulk delete in Spaces is now available\*\*\*]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><em>It's the little things</em>: Bulk delete in Spaces is now available***</p>
<p><img src="../changelog/images/bulk_delete_sm.gif" alt="image"></p>
<p>We’ve added a new feature that allows for the selection and bulk deletion of<br>
Spaces from your list. This enhancement is particularly beneficial for customers<br>
managing numerous Spaces, as it eliminates the need to delete each Space<br>
individually, streamlining the process and saving time. Enjoy!</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#11172023</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-11-17-2023-spaces</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[spaces]]></category>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2023 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New: Column Visibility Control with Local Storage Memory]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>New: Column Visibility Control with Local Storage Memory</strong></p>
<p><img src="../changelog/images/column_hiding.gif" alt="image"></p>
<p>We've introduced a new feature that allows for selective hiding or showing of<br>
columns, enabling users to customize their view for more focused work.<br>
Additionally, your column visibility preferences will now be automatically saved<br>
to local storage, ensuring that your personalized settings are remembered for<br>
future sessions. This update aims to enhance user efficiency by allowing you to<br>
tailor the interface to your specific needs and workflow.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#11172023</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-11-17-2023-spaces</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[spaces]]></category>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2023 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Guests can now be named in a Spaces URL]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Guests can now be named in a Spaces URL</strong></p>
<p>Previously, accessing Flatfile either directly through a URL or via an iframe<br>
with an <code>accessToken</code> would categorize all user activities under an anonymous<br>
guest. Now, if you know the <code>guestId</code>, interactions in Flatfile can be tied back<br>
to that person.</p>
<p>This is made possible with a new endpoint, <strong>/guests/:guestId/token</strong>, which<br>
generates an accessToken, and can be used to load the Flatfile space at<br>
<strong>http://platform.flatfile.com/space/:spaceId?token=:accessToken</strong>.</p>
<p>With this method, Guests are now accurately named and identifiable, enhancing<br>
user recognition and auditing.</p>
<p><a href="https://reference.flatfile.com/api-reference/guests/get-guest-token">See the endpoint</a>.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#11172023</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-11-17-2023-spaces</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[spaces]]></category>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2023 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Speed Optimization for Large Enum Lists]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Speed Optimization for Large Enum Lists</strong></p>
<p>When either the source (file) or destination (Blueprint) list contains more than<br>
100 enums, our mapping AI will now utilize a simplified algorithm. This change<br>
addresses scenarios where customers have extensive enum lists, such as 5,000<br>
different Shopify products, which previously slowed down our assignment<br>
algorithm. With this update, the execution speed for such extensive lists will<br>
be faster, ensuring a more efficient and responsive experience for clients with<br>
large datasets.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#11172023</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-11-17-2023-files</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[files]]></category>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2023 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fixed File Extraction for Workbook-Only Guests]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Fixed File Extraction for Workbook-Only Guests</strong></p>
<p>We’ve fixed an issue where guests with<br>
<a href="../developer-tools/security/roles-and-permissions#workbook-grant">workbook-only access</a><br>
could upload files but couldn’t extract them due to access restrictions. Guests<br>
can now upload and extract files smoothly in workbooks they have access to.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#11172023</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-11-17-2023-files</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[files]]></category>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2023 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Full Whitelabeling now available in Pro+]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Full Whitelabeling now available in Pro+</strong></p>
<p><img src="../changelog/images/whitelabeling.png" alt="image"></p>
<p>There are a few places where the Flatfile logo appears to your end customers.</p>
<ol>
<li>The <strong>Powered By Flatfile</strong> logo appears in the bottom right of Workbooks.</li>
<li>When sending invitations to Users or Guests, the Flatfile logo is included at<br>
the top of the emails.</li>
</ol>
<p>For those seeking a complete white-labeling experience, we offer a fully<br>
customizable solution as part of our Pro plans and above. Feel free to get in<br>
touch with us at <a href="mailto:support@flatfile.com">support@flatfile.com</a> to discuss<br>
the possibilities of a fully whitelabeled experience tailored to your needs.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#11132023</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-11-13-2023-spaces</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[spaces]]></category>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2023 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hide the info Tooltip]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Hide the info Tooltip</strong></p>
<p><img src="../changelog/images/infotooltip.png" alt="image"></p>
<p>Within each Space, we've implemented an informative tooltip providing essential<br>
details about the Space. This tooltip serves as valuable support for addressing<br>
customer inquiries and issues. However, we understand that there are scenarios<br>
where you may prefer to hide this information from your customers.</p>
<p>To accommodate your preferences, we've introduced the option to hide this Space<br>
tooltip. To make this adjustment, you can utilize the &quot;Update Environment&quot; patch<br>
available in our<br>
<a href="https://reference.flatfile.com/api-reference/environments/update-an-environment">API Reference</a>.</p>
<pre><code class="language-jsx">metadata: {
  showSpaceInfo: false;
}
</code></pre>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#11132023</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-11-13-2023-spaces</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[spaces]]></category>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2023 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[In this update, we've implemented a crucial enhancement by unifying the casing]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>In this update, we've implemented a crucial enhancement by unifying the casing<br>
in our API. We've resolved issues where certain properties were inconsistently<br>
cased, which had previously hindered their proper setting and retrieval.</p>
<p>With this unification, you can now seamlessly interact with our API, ensuring a<br>
smoother and more reliable experience.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#11132023</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-11-13-2023-core</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[core]]></category>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2023 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Previously, if an existing value was present in the enum field, you couldn't]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Previously, if an existing value was present in the enum field, you couldn't<br>
select a different value from the dropdown. Additionally, when a dropdown field<br>
was empty, you were unable to use the dropdown to select a valid option, and<br>
typing out an option wasn't possible either. Both of these limitations have now<br>
been resolved.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#11132023</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-11-13-2023-dataxp</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[dataxp]]></category>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2023 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Control your mapping accuracy]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Control your mapping accuracy</strong></p>
<p>We're excited to announce a new parameter within Sheet configuration, aptly<br>
named <code>mappingConfidenceThreshold</code>. This parameter empowers you to fine-tune<br>
your experience when working with automatically suggested fields during mapping<br>
jobs.</p>
<p>With <code>mappingConfidenceThreshold</code>, you have the flexibility to configure the<br>
minimum required confidence level. Think of it as a precision control, offering<br>
you the choice between conservative (exact match) or liberal (fuzzy matching)<br>
settings.</p>
<p><strong>How it works</strong></p>
<p>Set the value greater than 0 and up to a maximum of 1, for a more precise<br>
control over the mapping process:</p>
<pre><code class="language-jsx workbook.js">  sheets: [
    mappingConfidenceThreshold: .6,
    {...}
  ]
</code></pre>
<p><a href="../blueprint/sheet-options#mappingConfidenceThreshold">Learn more</a></p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#11072023</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-11-07-2023-dataxp</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[dataxp]]></category>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Nov 2023 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[More Precise Filtering is now Available]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>More Precise Filtering is now Available</strong></p>
<p>Now, FFQL queries made via filter: in the the search bar can be seamlessly<br>
combined with other filters. Whether you prefer using tabbed filters like<br>
“valid” and “error,” or you rely on the “Filter By Value” menu, you can now<br>
harness the power of FFQL alongside these filters.</p>
<p>With this update, you’ll experience precise narrowing of row results every time<br>
you apply FFQL queries in conjunction with other filters. No more guesswork—your<br>
filtered results will be spot on, making it easier than ever to find the<br>
information you need with pinpoint accuracy.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#11072023</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-11-07-2023-dataxp</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[dataxp]]></category>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Nov 2023 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Theming Column Headers]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Theming Column Headers</strong></p>
<p><img src="../changelog/images/fontinheader.png" alt="image"></p>
<p>You can now control the font of the headers in a table using the<br>
<code>column.header.fontFamily</code> property.</p>
<p><a href="../guides/theming#theme-table">Learn more</a></p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#11072023</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-11-07-2023-theming</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[theming]]></category>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Nov 2023 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Enhanced Cell Copying with Multi-line Preservation]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Enhanced Cell Copying with Multi-line Preservation</strong></p>
<p>We've improved the functionality for copying cells from external spreadsheets<br>
into our system. Now, when you copy cells containing more than one line, these<br>
new lines are preserved in the cell value upon pasting.</p>
<p>While these additional lines may not be visually apparent in the table, you can<br>
verify their presence by inspecting the data through the API, or by copying and<br>
pasting the cell content into another application.</p>
<p>This update ensures better data integrity and consistency when transferring<br>
content with complex formatting.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#11012023</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-11-01-2023-dataxp</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[dataxp]]></category>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Removed Character Limit on Mappings, Jobs, and Enum Mappings]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Removed Character Limit on Mappings, Jobs, and Enum Mappings</strong></p>
<p>We have lifted the previous 255-character limit for mappings, jobs, and enum<br>
mappings. This update allows for greater flexibility and more detailed entries<br>
in these areas.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#10302023</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-10-30-2023-spaces</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[spaces]]></category>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New API Feature to Restore Archived Spaces]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>New API Feature to Restore Archived Spaces</strong></p>
<p>API users now have the capability to restore an archived space. This can be done<br>
by setting the <code>archivedAt</code> property of the space to null via the<br>
<code>PATCH /spaces/:spaceId</code> endpoint.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#10302023</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-10-30-2023-spaces</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[spaces]]></category>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Improved Cascade Deletion for Spaces, Workbooks, and Sheets]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Improved Cascade Deletion for Spaces, Workbooks, and Sheets</strong></p>
<p>We've enhanced the deletion process for Spaces. In the past, deleting a Space<br>
did not automatically cascade to its Workbooks and Sheets. Now, with the latest<br>
update, soft deleting a Space will also soft delete its associated Workbooks and<br>
Sheets.</p>
<p>Furthermore, we've refined the <code>GET /workbooks</code> query. It now filters out<br>
workbooks linked to previously deleted Spaces, ensuring that only relevant and<br>
active workbooks are displayed. This update is helpful for Spaces deleted before<br>
this improvement was implemented.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#10302023</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-10-30-2023-spaces</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[spaces]]></category>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Enhanced Display of Enum Options in Turntable]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Enhanced Display of Enum Options in Turntable</strong></p>
<p>We've addressed an issue in the table where enum options without a label were<br>
incorrectly displaying as 'undefined'. With the latest update, in cases where an<br>
enum option lacks a label, the table will now default to showing the option's<br>
value instead.</p>
<p>This ensures a more accurate and user-friendly display of data.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#10302023</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-10-30-2023-spaces</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[spaces]]></category>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Disable Actions while Hooks are Running]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Disable Actions while Hooks are Running</strong></p>
<p><img src="../changelog/images/trackChanges.gif" alt="image"></p>
<p>Previously, developers faced challenges in determining when all hooks had<br>
finished running, essential for ensuring data transformation completion and<br>
preventing unintended data egress. As a workaround, they resorted to creating<br>
placeholder fields that defaulted to invalid states. When a hook completed<br>
processing for a record, it marked the field as valid, allowing submission only<br>
when there were no errors in this field.</p>
<p>Now, we're thrilled to introduce a solution to simplify this process—an all-new<br>
event: <code>commit:completed</code>. This event signals the end of all processing tasks.</p>
<pre><code class="language-jsx">settings: [{ trackChanges: true }];
</code></pre>
<p>Add a <code>settings</code> parameter in your sheet that includes <code>trackChanges: true,</code> to<br>
disable actions on both Sheets and Workbooks until any pending commits have been<br>
completed.</p>
<p><a href="../blueprint/sheet-options#settings">Learn more</a></p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#10252023</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-10-25-2023-spaces</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[spaces]]></category>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Job Mode: `toolbar-blocking`]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>New Job Mode: <code>toolbar-blocking</code></strong></p>
<p>We're excited to introduce a third job mode called <code>toolbarBlocking</code> alongside<br>
the existing <code>foreground</code> and <code>background</code> modes. With this new mode,<br>
<code>toolbarBlocking</code>, you have the flexibility to disable the Sheet Toolbar and<br>
Column Header Menus while still allowing users to enter records manually.</p>
<p><a href="../orchestration/actions#optional-parameters">Learn more</a></p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#10252023</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-10-25-2023-spaces</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[spaces]]></category>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Improved copy-paste experience while bulk selecting cells]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Improved copy-paste experience while bulk selecting cells</strong></p>
<p>We've enhanced the bulk selection experience by enabling paste functionality.<br>
When you paste, we simply transition you out of the selection state, similar to<br>
when editing. Note: if you paste without selecting any cells, the operation will<br>
automatically apply to the bulk-selected rows.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#10182023</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-10-18-2023-spaces</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[spaces]]></category>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[In the past, when your Space took more than 10 seconds to build, an "empty space]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>In the past, when your Space took more than 10 seconds to build, an &quot;empty space<br>
created&quot; message would appear. With our latest update, as long as you<br>
acknowledge the space:configure job, you can rest assured this dialog will no<br>
longer appear.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#10162023</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-10-16-2023-dataxp</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[dataxp]]></category>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New: Embed Sheets inside Documents]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>New: Embed Sheets inside Documents</strong></p>
<p>Now, by simply incorporating the <code>embed</code> HTML entity into your markdown body and<br>
providing the sheet ID, workbook ID, and name, you can effortlessly embed Sheets<br>
into Documents. Additionally, you have the flexibility to choose whether the<br>
embedded Sheet starts in an expanded or collapsed state when the document is<br>
loaded.</p>
<pre><code class="language-html">&lt;embed
  type=&quot;embedded-sheet&quot;
  name=&quot;Contacts&quot;
  defaultExpanded=&quot;true&quot;
  sheetId=&quot;your_sheet_id&quot;
  workbookId=&quot;your_workbook_id&quot;
/&gt;
</code></pre>
<p>This enhancement provides further freedom to tailor document-driven interactions<br>
precisely to your needs.</p>
<p><a href="../guides/documents#embedding-sheets-in-documents">Learn more</a></p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#10162023</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-10-16-2023-spaces</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[spaces]]></category>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Actions are now available on Documents.]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Actions are now available on Documents.</strong></p>
<p><img src="../changelog/images/document_actions_primary.png" alt="image"></p>
<p>Documents, which are standalone webpages within your Spaces, can now host a<br>
variety of actions, just like Workbooks, Sheets, and Files.</p>
<p>Document-Mounted Actions have their own configuration within a Document object.<br>
The executable code within an Action is compiled into a Job entity, offering the<br>
flexibility to run asynchronously or immediately. This empowers you to create<br>
more interactive and dynamic Documents, enhancing the overall user experience<br>
within your Flatfile Spaces.</p>
<pre><code class="language-jsx workbook.js">//your document can now have an action that looks like this
actions: [
  {
    operation: 'sendAction',
    mode: 'foreground',
    label: 'Send to...',
    description: 'Send this page to someone.',
    primary: true,
  },
  {...}
]
</code></pre>
<p><a href="../guides/actions#document-mounted">Learn more</a></p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#10132023</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-10-13-2023-dataxp</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[dataxp]]></category>
            <pubDate>Fri, 13 Oct 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The API now supports two new actions: `sheets.lock` and `sheets.unlock`.]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>The API now supports two new actions: <code>sheets.lock</code> and <code>sheets.unlock</code>.</strong></p>
<p>With the introduction of these API actions, you gain the ability to manage sheet<br>
locking within your application. The <code>sheets.lock</code> action allows you to lock a<br>
sheet, preventing any further modifications to its content. Conversely, the<br>
<code>sheets.unlock</code> action enables you to release the lock and restore full editing<br>
capabilities to the sheet.</p>
<p>These new API actions provide greater control and flexibility when it comes to<br>
managing sheet access and data integrity.</p>
<p><a href="https://reference.flatfile.com/api-reference/sheets/lock-a-sheet">See the endpoint</a></p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#10112023</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-10-11-2023-spaces</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[spaces]]></category>
            <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New: Full-screen Documents!]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>New: Full-screen Documents!</strong></p>
<p>Documents have gained a new capability, allowing them to seamlessly transition<br>
into full-screen takeovers, thus removing their presence from the sidebar.</p>
<p><strong>How it works:</strong></p>
<p>To enable this functionality, we've introduced a new property on Documents:<br>
<code>treatments</code>. This property allows users to define specific descriptors for each<br>
Document. When a Document is assigned the &quot;ephemeral&quot; treatment, it will<br>
transform into a full-screen overlay, visible exclusively within the Spaces<br>
dashboard, while being discreetly tucked away from the Spaces sidebar.</p>
<p>This enhancement enhances user creativity and provides the freedom to tailor<br>
document-driven interactions precisely to their needs.</p>
<pre><code class="language-ts">await api.documents.create(spaceId, {
  treatments: [&quot;ephemeral&quot;],
  title: &quot;Getting Started&quot;,
});
</code></pre>
<p><a href="../guides/documents#ephemeral-documents">Learn more</a></p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#10112023</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-10-11-2023-spaces</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[spaces]]></category>
            <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[We’ve added Indonesia (ID) translations!]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>We’ve added Indonesia (ID) translations!</strong></p>
<p>Building upon our existing language support (based on your customers’ browser<br>
locale), which already included French, German, Portuguese and Spanish<br>
translations, we’ve expanded our capabilities to cater to an even broader<br>
audience.</p>
<p>Need another language? Let us know and we’ll prioritize getting it added.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#10112023</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-10-11-2023-spaces</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[spaces]]></category>
            <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Now Available: Set estimated time of completion on Jobs]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Now Available: Set estimated time of completion on Jobs</strong></p>
<p><img src="../changelog/images/estimatedTime_actions.png" alt="image"></p>
<p>When acknowledging a job from a Workbook or Sheet action, you now have the<br>
option to set the <code>estimatedCompletionAt</code> parameter. Setting the estimated time<br>
of completion for the job leads to more informative and interactive features in<br>
the UI.</p>
<ol>
<li><p>In the Foreground Job overlay, you'll see real-time progress displayed as a<br>
percentage, along with an estimate of the remaining time.</p></li>
<li><p>Additionally, the Jobs Panel will share visibility into the estimated<br>
remaining time for acknowledged jobs.</p></li>
</ol>
<p><a href="../guides/actions">Learn more about using Actions</a>.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#10092023</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-10-09-2023-dataxp</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[dataxp]]></category>
            <pubDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Previously, when uploading a file, actions could only be added to it after the]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Previously, when uploading a file, actions could only be added to it after the<br>
file was uploaded (by calling a file update via a listener). Now, with our<br>
latest update, you can now include actions during file upload allowing actions<br>
to be applied to the file immediately upon creation.</p>
<p>See the<br>
<a href="https://reference.flatfile.com/api-reference/files/upload-a-file">API Reference</a>.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#10092023</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-10-09-2023-files</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[files]]></category>
            <pubDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The find/replace operation is now able to handle large datasets. Now, records]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>The find/replace operation is now able to handle large datasets. Now, records<br>
are batched into groups of 10,000 rows, and a unique versionId is assigned to<br>
each batch. Additionally, the workbook service will emit events for each batch<br>
processed.</p>
<p>This improvement is particularly beneficial for @flatfile/plugin-record-hook,<br>
which can now retrieve and respond to all records in a single find/replace<br>
operation, thanks to the 10,000-row batching.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#10092023</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-10-09-2023-dataxp</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[dataxp]]></category>
            <pubDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[When adding a secret to a space via the API, we have expanded the flexibility of]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>When adding a secret to a space via the API, we have expanded the flexibility of<br>
secret names. While the API allows spaces within secret names, the UI previously<br>
restricted them by filtering spaces in the regex validation logic for Secret<br>
Names. With this update, space characters are now considered valid and accepted<br>
characters in secret names, aligning the behavior between the API and the UI.</p>
<p>Learn more about <a href="../guides/secrets">sharing secrets</a>.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#10092023</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-10-09-2023-core</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[core]]></category>
            <pubDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Now Available: Accept Dynamic Inputs on Actions]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Now Available: Accept Dynamic Inputs on Actions</strong></p>
<p><img src="../changelog/images/action_inputs.png" alt="image"></p>
<p>Now, when initiating an action, you have the option to gather additional<br>
information from end users to facilitate the successful completion of the<br>
intended task.</p>
<p><strong>Here’s how it works:</strong></p>
<p>Suppose you want to allow users to specify the name of the file they intend to<br>
export. In such cases, you can configure input fields for your action. When an<br>
end user triggers this action, a secondary dialog will appear, prompting them to<br>
provide the necessary information.</p>
<p><strong>The available input types include:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><code>string</code>: For capturing text-based information.</li>
<li><code>textarea</code>: Ideal for longer text entries or descriptions.</li>
<li><code>number</code>: To collect numeric data.</li>
<li><code>boolean</code>: For simple yes/no or true/false responses.</li>
<li><code>enum</code>: Enables users to select from a predefined list of options.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Two easy ways to get started:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Learn about all the parameters available on <code>inputForm</code> for Actions<br>
<a href="../orchestration/actions#inputform">here</a>.</li>
<li>Or follow this copy/paste <a href="../guides/actions#actions-with-input-forms">Guide</a><br>
to quickly see it in action in your code.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#10082023</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-10-08-2023-dataxp</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[dataxp]]></category>
            <pubDate>Sun, 08 Oct 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Exciting Update: Additional Fields]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Exciting Update: Additional Fields</strong></p>
<p><img src="../changelog/images/addl_fields.png" alt="image"></p>
<p>With additional fields, end users can seamlessly map to fields that don’t exist<br>
by simply adding a new property to any of your new or pre-existing Blueprint(s).</p>
<p>Here’s how it works:</p>
<ul>
<li>When you set allowAdditionalFields to true, your Sheet gains the ability to<br>
accept additional fields, extending beyond what’s originally specified in its<br>
configuration.</li>
<li>These extra fields can be incorporated, either through API integrations or by<br>
end users during the file import process.</li>
<li>Fields that go beyond the Blueprint’s initial setup are marked with a<br>
treatment property set to additional, ensuring complete transparency over what<br>
extends the Blueprint.</li>
<li>What’s more, adding a custom field is a breeze—its name will be automatically<br>
set to match the header name from the file being mapped. This simplifies the<br>
process.</li>
</ul>
<p><a href="../blueprint/sheet-options">See the docs</a>.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#10052023</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-10-05-2023-dataxp</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[dataxp]]></category>
            <pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Introducing New and Enhanced Event Logs]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Introducing New and Enhanced Event Logs</strong></p>
<p><img src="../changelog/images/event_logs.png" alt="image"></p>
<p>Our aim is to make it easy for everyone to monitor events, find problems, and<br>
help developers avoid overcomplicating their code with excessive Console logs<br>
that would need removal later.</p>
<p>With our enhanced Event logs, you can now:</p>
<ol>
<li>View a comprehensive list of logged events, categorized by event topic.</li>
<li>Easily discern the status of each event.</li>
<li>Gauge the execution time of each event.</li>
<li>Access events chronologically, with the most recent at the top.</li>
<li>Dive into each event for context and review any associated console logs.</li>
</ol>
<p>As an added bonus, you have the capability to filter events, focusing solely on<br>
failures.</p>
<p>See it live: <a href="http://platform.flatfile.com/logs">platform.flatfie.com/logs</a></p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#10022023</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-10-02-2023-spaces</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[spaces]]></category>
            <pubDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Choosing a `namespace` on Space creation is now easier than ever. Rather than]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Choosing a <code>namespace</code> on Space creation is now easier than ever. Rather than<br>
manually typing the namespaces into a free-form text field, you can simply<br>
choose from a dropdown menu of available options. The available namespaces are<br>
conveniently listed within the <code>namespaces</code> array of the Environment, providing<br>
a more efficient and accurate way to handle namespace selection.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#10022023</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-10-02-2023-spaces</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[spaces]]></category>
            <pubDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Previously, when using the find and replace feature, only the initial batch of]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Previously, when using the find and replace feature, only the initial batch of<br>
records had data hooks run again. Now, the find/replace operation efficiently<br>
groups records into batches of 10,000 rows, assigning a unique versionId to each<br>
batch. This improvement empowers record-hooks to process all records seamlessly<br>
within a single find/replace operation.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#10022023</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-10-02-2023-transform</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[transform]]></category>
            <pubDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Now, you can include a free-form JSON object as `metadata` on your Workbook,]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Now, you can include a free-form JSON object as <code>metadata</code> on your Workbook,<br>
providing you with a flexible way to store additional information related to it.<br>
Whether you're creating a new Workbook or updating an existing one, you have the<br>
option to enrich your Workbooks with meaningful metadata.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#10022023</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-10-02-2023-spaces</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[spaces]]></category>
            <pubDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Previously, when adding a secret to a space through the API, we supported spaces]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Previously, when adding a secret to a space through the API, we supported spaces<br>
in secret names. However, the UI had regex logic that filtered out spaces when<br>
validating secret names.</p>
<p>In this update, we've harmonized the process by accepting space characters as<br>
valid characters for secret names in both the API and the UI. Your secret names<br>
can now include spaces without any issues.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#10022023</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-10-02-2023-spaces</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[spaces]]></category>
            <pubDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[We've resolved an issue where long messages would overflow the cell in]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>We've resolved an issue where long messages would overflow the cell in<br>
validation messages. By implementing a straightforward <code>word-break</code> property,<br>
your validation messages will now display lengthy messages more elegantly.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#10022023</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-10-02-2023-dataxp</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[dataxp]]></category>
            <pubDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[We’ve added Portuguese (Brazilian) translations!]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>We’ve added Portuguese (Brazilian) translations!</strong></p>
<p>Building upon our existing language support (based on your customers’ browser<br>
locale), which already included French, German, and Spanish translations, we’ve<br>
expanded our capabilities to cater to an even broader audience.</p>
<p>Need another language? Let us know and we’ll prioritize getting it added.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#09272023</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-09-27-2023-spaces</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[spaces]]></category>
            <pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Enhanced Document Customization with Markdown & HTML Support]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Enhanced Document Customization with Markdown &amp; HTML Support</strong></p>
<p>Until now, you could only utilize Markdown for your Documents. However, we're<br>
excited to inform you that HTML support has been seamlessly integrated, offering<br>
you even more versatility to tailor your Documents exactly to your liking.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#09272023</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-09-27-2023-spaces</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[spaces]]></category>
            <pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[We've revamped the way partial replaces work, enhancing your data editing]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>We've revamped the way partial replaces work, enhancing your data editing<br>
experience for maximum smoothness and intuitiveness. In the past, when you<br>
attempted to replace specific characters with an empty string (&quot;&quot;), it<br>
occasionally resulted in the cell value becoming null, which wasn't quite what<br>
you had in mind.</p>
<p>For instance, if you needed to eliminate dashes from UUID fields, you'd<br>
naturally want &quot;abc-123&quot; to transform into &quot;abc123&quot; rather than mysteriously<br>
turning null.</p>
<p>We value your feedback. Now, you can confidently perform partial replacements<br>
without the hassle of unexpected null values.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#09222023</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-09-22-2023-dataxp</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[dataxp]]></category>
            <pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[We've made improvements behind the scenes to ensure that your data gets mapped]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>We've made improvements behind the scenes to ensure that your data gets mapped<br>
with more precision. Previously, some data could be missed during mapping, but<br>
now, we're considering both the option labels and values, making sure nothing is<br>
left behind. This means you'll have a smoother and more reliable experience when<br>
mapping your data, ensuring that everything is captured correctly.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#09222023</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-09-22-2023-files</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[files]]></category>
            <pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Localization is Now Available]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Localization is Now Available</strong></p>
<p><img src="../changelog/images/localization.png" alt="image"></p>
<p>We are excited to introduce localization features in Flatfile! Now, your<br>
customers will enjoy automatic translations based on their browser locale,<br>
including French, German, and Spanish.</p>
<p>Key Features:</p>
<ul>
<li>Translations are exclusively applied in Spaces (guest areas).</li>
<li>Our user-friendly guide will assist you in effortlessly translating and<br>
personalizing the content within your space, whether it's custom actions,<br>
documents, and more.</li>
<li>Require another language? Send us a note, and we'll make it a priority to<br>
include it.</li>
</ul>
<p><a href="../guides/localization">Follow the guide</a> or try the<br>
<a href="https://platform.flatfile.com/getting-started">Localization demo Space</a> to get<br>
started.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#09202023</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-09-20-2023-spaces</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[spaces]]></category>
            <pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New: Promote Sheet Actions]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>New: Promote Sheet Actions</strong></p>
<p><img src="../changelog/images/primary_actions.png" alt="image"></p>
<p>Previously, the <code>primary:true</code> concept on Actions didn't affect Sheet actions,<br>
leaving them all in the &quot;more actions&quot; drop-down. But now, setting primary to<br>
true will showcase these actions right in the Sheet toolbar, as buttons with<br>
clear, user-friendly text.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#09202023</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-09-20-2023-dataxp</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[dataxp]]></category>
            <pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[You can now effortlessly view up to 500k records at once. When you reach the end]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>You can now effortlessly view up to 500k records at once. When you reach the end<br>
of the table, a helpful message will appear, reminding you that there's more<br>
data waiting. Simply search or filter to reduce the size of your dataset and<br>
access it all. This change was added due to browser limitations that restrict<br>
maximum height in the DOM.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#09202023</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-09-20-2023-dataxp</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[dataxp]]></category>
            <pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Introducing: Code Blocks for Documents]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Introducing: Code Blocks for Documents</strong></p>
<p><img src="../changelog/images/documents_codeblocks.png" alt="image"></p>
<p>We've introduced the ability to add code blocks to your Documents. You can now<br>
use the following syntax to define code blocks and specify the language:</p>
<p><img src="../changelog/images/documents_codeblocks_sample.png" alt="image"></p>
<p>Your code will be formatted accordingly, enhancing the clarity and presentation<br>
of your content.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#09152023</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-09-15-2023-spaces</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[spaces]]></category>
            <pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Previously, guests without access to the specific workbook would encounter a]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Previously, guests without access to the specific workbook would encounter a<br>
&quot;Workbook Not Found&quot; error. Now, a fallback mechanism has been implemented to<br>
validate access to the <code>primaryWorkbook</code>, ensuring a smoother experience for<br>
users.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#09152023</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-09-15-2023-spaces</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[spaces]]></category>
            <pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Introducing support for finding empty fields in ffql using the syntax:]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Introducing support for finding empty fields in ffql using the syntax:</p>
<pre><code class="language-jsx">filter: first_name eq &quot;&quot;
</code></pre>
<p>Now, you can easily query and filter records with empty values.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#09132023</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-09-13-2023-dataxp</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[dataxp]]></category>
            <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Resolved an issue where attempting to upsert an Environment secret that was]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Resolved an issue where attempting to upsert an Environment secret that was<br>
already defined within a Space was not functioning as expected. This fix ensures<br>
proper handling when upserting a secret into an Environment after specifying a<br>
Space ID.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#09132023</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-09-13-2023-core</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[core]]></category>
            <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Resolved an issue where the import button could prematurely appear before a file]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Resolved an issue where the import button could prematurely appear before a file<br>
was ready to be imported. This was due to an early update of the file's status<br>
with a workbook ID, which has now been adjusted to wait until the data is<br>
queriable before updating. The import process now aligns better with the file's<br>
readiness.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#09132023</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-09-13-2023-files</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[files]]></category>
            <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Experience improved performance (for instance, when scrolling to the bottom of]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Experience improved performance (for instance, when scrolling to the bottom of<br>
the data table) with large workbooks as we've optimized query clauses and<br>
updated indexes. Plus, we've seamlessly migrated all existing workbooks to<br>
benefit from these enhancements.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#09132023</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-09-13-2023-dataxp</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[dataxp]]></category>
            <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[When a file stream becomes unreadable due to file malformation, improvements]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>When a file stream becomes unreadable due to file malformation, improvements<br>
were made to ensure that any errors are correctly communicated to the UI.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#09112023</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-09-11-2023-files</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[files]]></category>
            <pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Experience improved performance (for instance, when scrolling to the bottom of]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Experience improved performance (for instance, when scrolling to the bottom of<br>
the data table) with large workbooks as we've optimized query clauses and<br>
updated indexes. Plus, we've seamlessly migrated all existing workbooks to<br>
benefit from these enhancements.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#09112023</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-09-11-2023-files</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[files]]></category>
            <pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Documents in the sidebar are now organized based on their creation date. This]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Documents in the sidebar are now organized based on their creation date. This<br>
enhancement helps developers have more control the order of their Documents.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#09082023</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-09-08-2023-dataxp</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[dataxp]]></category>
            <pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[If you have access to multiple Spaces, you'll notice a dropdown menu at the top]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>If you have access to multiple Spaces, you'll notice a dropdown menu at the top<br>
left corner of each Space. Previously, there was an issue where all the data<br>
within the Space would update correctly, except for Workbooks/Sheets in the<br>
sidebar. This issue has been successfully resolved.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#09082023</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-09-08-2023-spaces</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[spaces]]></category>
            <pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2 new Demo spaces were added: Documents & Theming. In these demo Spaces, you'll]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>2 new Demo spaces were added: Documents &amp; Theming. In these demo Spaces, you'll<br>
learn how to:</p>
<ol>
<li>Add Markdown + HTML Documents to your Space</li>
<li>Customize the look and feel of Flatfile to match your brand</li>
</ol>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#09082023</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-09-08-2023-dataxp</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[dataxp]]></category>
            <pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[We've extended the `job:ready` timeout to 10 minutes, aligning it with the]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>We've extended the <code>job:ready</code> timeout to 10 minutes, aligning it with the<br>
extractor timeout. This adjustment provides more time for all jobs running<br>
within an Agent.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#09082023</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-09-08-2023-dataxp</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[dataxp]]></category>
            <pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Job Outcome Acknowledgements]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>New Job Outcome Acknowledgements</strong></p>
<p><strong><code>acknowledge: false</code></strong></p>
<p><img src="../changelog/images/outcome_modal.png" alt="image"></p>
<p>By default, job outcomes are reported through a toast notification in the<br>
top-right corner. To utilize this, simply set <code>outcome =&gt; message</code>. This<br>
approach ensures that your job completion status is promptly communicated to the<br>
end user.</p>
<p><strong><code>acknowledge: true</code></strong></p>
<p><img src="../changelog/images/outcome_fullscreen.png" alt="image"></p>
<p>When the <code>acknowledge</code> option is configured as <code>true</code>, a persistent full-screen<br>
modal is presented. This modal remains visible until the user interacts by<br>
clicking the &quot;Continue&quot; button, acknowledging the outcome.</p>
<p><strong>Usage</strong></p>
<pre><code class="language-jsx">await api.jobs.complete(jobId, {
  outcome: {
    acknowlege: true,
    message: &quot;Text here.&quot;,
  },
});
</code></pre>
<p>This enhancement provides flexibility in how you choose to inform users about<br>
job outcomes. <a href="../guides/actions#usage">Learn more</a>.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#09062023</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-09-06-2023-dataxp</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[dataxp]]></category>
            <pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Enhanced Job Outcomes with Next Action Links]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Enhanced Job Outcomes with Next Action Links</strong></p>
<p>Job outcomes have been upgraded to support <code>next</code> action links. Now, you can<br>
display links to external URLs, trigger downloads, or retry jobes upon job<br>
completion/failure.</p>
<p><strong>Usage</strong></p>
<pre><code class="language-jsx listener">await api.jobs.complete(jobId, {
  outcome: {
    next: Url | Download | Retry,
    message: &quot;Text here.&quot;,
  },
});
</code></pre>
<p>This improvement adds versatility and flexibility to your job outcomes,<br>
enhancing user interaction and experience.</p>
<p><a href="../orchestration/jobs#next-links">Learn more</a>.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#09062023</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-09-06-2023-dataxp</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[dataxp]]></category>
            <pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Enhanced Action Button Behavior]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Enhanced Action Button Behavior</strong></p>
<p><img src="../changelog/images/hasAllValid.gif" alt="image"></p>
<p>Two key enhancements to Actions have been introduced:</p>
<p><strong>Disable Actions When Invalid Records</strong>: Developers can now add an optional<br>
flag to Actions, preventing users from initiating Actions when Sheets or<br>
Workbooks contain invalid records. This helps avoid unnecessary job failures and<br>
ensures Actions are performed on valid data.</p>
<pre><code class="language-jsx">constraints: [{ type: 'hasAllValid' }],
</code></pre>
<p><strong>Disable Actions When No Selected Records:</strong> To enhance the user experience,<br>
we've introduced the <code>hasSelection</code> flag. When added as a constraint, this flag<br>
disables Actions if no records are selected in the Sheet or Workbook, ensuring<br>
Actions are only triggered when relevant data is chosen.</p>
<pre><code class="language-jsx">constraints: [ { type: 'hasSelection' }],
</code></pre>
<p><a href="../orchestration/actions#optional-parameters">Learn more</a>.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#09062023</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-09-06-2023-dataxp</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[dataxp]]></category>
            <pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Improved FFQL handling of dates and number comparisons]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Improved FFQL handling of dates and number comparisons</strong></p>
<p><strong>Enhanced Number Field Queries:</strong></p>
<p>When conducting equality or inequality FFQL comparisons for <code>number</code> fields, the<br>
query value is now cast to a number and then compared with the parsed &quot;shadow&quot;<br>
value. This rectifies issues related to numeric comparisons. Additionally, we've<br>
resolved a bug where numbers with no digits before the decimal point (e.g.,<br>
&quot;.3&quot;) were not being properly parsed into shadow values.</p>
<p><strong>Advanced Date Field Handling:</strong></p>
<p>For <code>date</code> fields, query values are now attempted to be parsed into dates. On<br>
the SQL side, a <code>CASE</code> statement is employed to parse the stored values into<br>
dates for accurate comparison. To accommodate SQL-side date parsing<br>
requirements, we've integrated a regex pattern to detect <code>YYYY-MM-DD</code>, <code>m/d/yy</code>,<br>
and <code>m/d/yyyy</code> formats. This ensures correct parsing and comparison of date<br>
values.</p>
<p><strong>Fix for Invalid Number Input:</strong></p>
<p>We've resolved a bug where changing a number field to an invalid number left the<br>
previous &quot;shadow&quot; value intact. Now, in such cases, the previous shadow value is<br>
properly cleared, leading to consistent and accurate behavior.</p>
<p>These updates contribute to improved query handling, better data integrity, and<br>
a more seamless experience when working with number and date fields.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#09012023</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-09-01-2023-dataxp</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[dataxp]]></category>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Introducing caching for record counts, resulting in improved performance for API]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Introducing caching for record counts, resulting in improved performance for API<br>
requests.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#09012023</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-09-01-2023-core</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[core]]></category>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The `PATCH /sheets` endpoint has been upgraded to accept both an array of]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>The <code>PATCH /sheets</code> endpoint has been upgraded to accept both an array of<br>
SheetUpdates and an array of SheetConfigs (backwards compatible). This expanded<br>
capability empowers users with more flexible and efficient options when updating<br>
Sheets.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#09012023</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-09-01-2023-core</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[core]]></category>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[![image](../changelog/images/tooltips-actions.png)]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1><img src="../changelog/images/tooltips-actions.png" alt="image"></h1>
<p>We've introduced a new parameter: <code>tooltip</code> to Actions, allowing the addition of<br>
tooltips. These tooltips are now visible in the user interface for both buttons<br>
and list items whenever the associated Action is enabled. This enhancement<br>
provides users with clear and context-aware explanations for enabled Actions,<br>
contributing to an improved overall user experience.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#09012023</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-09-01-2023-dataxp</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[dataxp]]></category>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fixed a cosmetic issue with scrolling through Workbooks. The problem stemmed]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Fixed a cosmetic issue with scrolling through Workbooks. The problem stemmed<br>
from the outer container scrolling based on the inner content's height. By<br>
applying overflow properties to the inner component, which holds a list of items<br>
within a flex container, we have resolved this issue.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#09012023</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-09-01-2023-dataxp</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[dataxp]]></category>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[🚀 4 New Example Spaces]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>🚀 4 New Example Spaces</strong></p>
<p>Visit the <strong>Getting Started</strong> page on your Dashboard to discover four new<br>
options for effortlessly generating demo spaces:</p>
<ol>
<li>Namespaces</li>
<li>Metadata</li>
<li>Egress</li>
<li>Sidebar Customization</li>
</ol>
<p>Similar to the rest of the options, we've provided the underlying code for each<br>
Space, simplifying the process of breaking down and comprehending the elements<br>
on display.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#08302023</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-08-30-2023-spaces</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[spaces]]></category>
            <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Authentication Query Enhancement]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Authentication Query Enhancement</strong></p>
<p>The authentication query has been streamlined for optimized performance.<br>
Extensive benchmarking has revealed that this refinement contributes to a<br>
reduction of approximately 20 milliseconds for each request. This enhancement<br>
results in faster overall processing and improved response times.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#08302023</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-08-30-2023-core</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[core]]></category>
            <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The **Data Checklist** now includes data types that correspond to each field.]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>The <strong>Data Checklist</strong> now includes data types that correspond to each field.<br>
Additionally, the searchable dropdowns are now more user friendly.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#08302023</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-08-30-2023-dataxp</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[dataxp]]></category>
            <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A pagination logic issue concerning **Environments** has been resolved. The]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>A pagination logic issue concerning <strong>Environments</strong> has been resolved. The<br>
correction ensures accurate calculation of the number of pages and consistent<br>
delivery of valid responses in accordance with the<br>
<a href="https://flatfile.stoplight.io/docs/api/1dcb99aada63f-pagination">Pagination</a><br>
type.</p>
<p>Furthermore, the default page size for <strong>Spaces</strong> has been set to 10, aligning<br>
it with the specifications outlined in the API documentation.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#08302023</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-08-30-2023-core</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[core]]></category>
            <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Previously, attempting to navigate into a dropdown using the keyboard's tab key]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Previously, attempting to navigate into a dropdown using the keyboard's tab key<br>
was unresponsive. This issue has been addressed, and tabbing via keyboard now<br>
smoothly activates dropdowns, accompanied by a focus outline for the custom<br>
trigger.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#08302023</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-08-30-2023-dataxp</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[dataxp]]></category>
            <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The API specification has been updated to facilitate the mapping of `enum`]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>The API specification has been updated to facilitate the mapping of <code>enum</code><br>
values of various types such as <code>string</code>, <code>integer</code>, or <code>boolean</code>. This<br>
modification effectively resolves a server error response that was previously<br>
encountered when utilizing such <code>enum</code> values within the API.</p>
<p>In addition, the loading state of the &quot;Continue&quot; button has been refined to<br>
ensure smooth recovery from server errors. This adjustment enhances the overall<br>
user experience by providing more graceful handling of unexpected issues during<br>
the process.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#08302023</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-08-30-2023-core</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[core]]></category>
            <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[🚀 Instant Extraction for CSV/TSV/PSV Files]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>🚀 Instant Extraction for CSV/TSV/PSV Files</strong></p>
<p>With the removal of the extraction step for CSV/TSV/PSV files, the import<br>
experience is now more seamless than ever. As soon as the upload is complete,<br>
these files are instantly extracted, ensuring an efficient and immediate<br>
handling of your data.</p>
<p>The impact of this change is remarkable. What used to take approximately 3 and a<br>
half minutes to extract now concludes in less than 10 seconds.</p>
<p>In addition, we now natively support TSV and PSV files meaning you don't need to<br>
use an extractor plugin to support these file types.</p>
<p>While speed is the prime advantage, this upgrade doesn’t merely boost<br>
performance. It also simplifies and enhances reliability in our system.<br>
Previously, concerns about only a fraction of a file being extracted are now<br>
history. Furthermore, this approach strategically eases the load on our<br>
database, reducing the likelihood of encountering resource limits.</p>
<p>In essence, it’s a win-win for both efficiency and user experience.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#08252023</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-08-25-2023-spaces</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[spaces]]></category>
            <pubDate>Fri, 25 Aug 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[🚀 A Revamped Starting Point]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>🚀 A Revamped Starting Point</strong></p>
<p><img src="../changelog/images/get-started.png" alt="image"></p>
<p>Navigate to your Dashboard's Getting Started page to find an array of new<br>
options for effortlessly creating demo spaces. Additionally, we've included the<br>
underlying code for each Space, making it straightforward to deconstruct and<br>
understand what you're seeing.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#08242023</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-08-24-2023-spaces</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[spaces]]></category>
            <pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[🚀 Major improvements to our queue system]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>🚀 Major improvements to our queue system</strong></p>
<p>We’ve implemented a state-of-the-art technology to substantially enhance the<br>
reliability and performance of our queue system. This improvement has a profound<br>
impact on the execution of asynchronous tasks, like data validation.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#08242023</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-08-24-2023-infra</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[infra]]></category>
            <pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Now, you can set a description for each Option Field value via API. End users]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Now, you can set a description for each Option Field value via API. End users<br>
can then view this description as a tooltip during mapping.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#08242023</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-08-24-2023-files</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[files]]></category>
            <pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[We've added new API routes to capture up to 5 snapshots of a Sheet, with the]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>We've added new API routes to capture up to 5 snapshots of a Sheet, with the<br>
flexibility to restore any of them using the API at your convenience. Stay tuned<br>
as we prepare to bring this functionality to the UI as well.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#08242023</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-08-24-2023-dataxp</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[dataxp]]></category>
            <pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A Sheet with no access enabled (`access:[]`) now shows a lock icon on the Sheet]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>A Sheet with no access enabled (<code>access:[]</code>) now shows a lock icon on the Sheet<br>
tab.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#08242023</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-08-24-2023-dataxp</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[dataxp]]></category>
            <pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[We opted to hide the files count on the Files page if there are no files.]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>We opted to hide the files count on the Files page if there are no files.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#08242023</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-08-24-2023-files</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[files]]></category>
            <pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A shrimp size update to the colors of the sidebar toggle so it looks good with]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>A shrimp size update to the colors of the sidebar toggle so it looks good with<br>
all themes.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#08242023</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-08-24-2023-files</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[files]]></category>
            <pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Info inside `metadata` > `userInfo` will now display in the Spaces list.]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Info inside <code>metadata</code> &gt; <code>userInfo</code> will now display in the Spaces list.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#08242023</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-08-24-2023-spaces</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[spaces]]></category>
            <pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Metadata allows you to store and retrieve additional data about a Space, Record,]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Metadata allows you to store and retrieve additional data about a Space, Record,<br>
or Field without exposing it to end users. Now, Environments also have a<br>
<code>metadata</code> string array.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#08242023</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-08-24-2023-spaces</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[spaces]]></category>
            <pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[We made a small fix to allow better vertical scrolling in the Dashboard sidebar.]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>We made a small fix to allow better vertical scrolling in the Dashboard sidebar.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#08242023</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-08-24-2023-spaces</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[spaces]]></category>
            <pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[CTRL + Z wasn't working for a minute. This is now fixed.]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>CTRL + Z wasn't working for a minute. This is now fixed.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#08242023</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-08-24-2023-dataxp</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[dataxp]]></category>
            <pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[If a boolean cell is empty, we only show the toggle on hover now.]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>If a boolean cell is empty, we only show the toggle on hover now.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#08242023</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-08-24-2023-dataxp</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[dataxp]]></category>
            <pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[We were seeing issues where corrupt files that ran through extraction did not]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>We were seeing issues where corrupt files that ran through extraction did not<br>
fail but simply skipped over the lines affected. This is now resolved.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#08242023</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-08-24-2023-files</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[files]]></category>
            <pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[🚀 Introducing Command+k Triggered Search and Transformation (Early Access)]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><strong>🚀 Introducing Command+k Triggered Search and Transformation (Early Access)</strong></p>
<p><img src="../changelog/images/AI-assist.png" alt="image"></p>
<p>This update enhances your workflow by centralizing experiences under the<br>
Command+k shortcut.</p>
<p>A straightforward forward slash, followed by these options, grants access to our<br>
data transformation and query tools:</p>
<ul>
<li><code>/transform</code> (AI-powered)</li>
<li><code>/query</code> (AI-powered)</li>
<li><code>/search</code> (global search)</li>
<li><code>/filter</code> (Flatfile Query Language, ffql)</li>
<li><code>/in</code> (field-specific search)</li>
</ul>
<p>Chat with us or email <a href="mailto:support@flatfile.com">support@flatfile.com</a> to<br>
have this feature flagged on in your Account today!</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#08202023</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-08-20-2023-dataxp</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[dataxp]]></category>
            <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[There is now a count at the top of the files list that shows the total number of]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>There is now a count at the top of the files list that shows the total number of<br>
files.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#08202023</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-08-20-2023-dataxp</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[dataxp]]></category>
            <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[![image](../changelog/images/sidebar_collapsed.png)]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p><img src="../changelog/images/sidebar_collapsed.png" alt="image"></p>
<p>The Sidebar now has three different states:</p>
<ul>
<li>Collapsed state</li>
<li>Open state</li>
<li>Totally hidden state</li>
</ul>
<p>Additionally, the Sidebar will now automatically collapse itself on smaller<br>
screens.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#08202023</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-08-20-2023-spaces</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[spaces]]></category>
            <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[We now handle overflowing space name(s) by:]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>We now handle overflowing space name(s) by:</p>
<ul>
<li>Breaking the word</li>
<li>Limiting the name to two lines and giving it an ellipsis if it overflows</li>
<li>Adding a tooltip with the space name to truncated names</li>
<li>Previously, badge names in the data checklist could break to two lines making<br>
them hard to read. This is also fixed.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#08202023</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-08-20-2023-spaces</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[spaces]]></category>
            <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[When determining the lighter shades of each main theme colors, i.e. primary,]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>When determining the lighter shades of each main theme colors, i.e. primary,<br>
danger, warning and success, there are now checks to ensure no colors end up as<br>
white.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#08202023</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-08-20-2023-theming</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[theming]]></category>
            <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The filename was added to the mapping scene so users can now see which file they]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>The filename was added to the mapping scene so users can now see which file they<br>
are currently mapping.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#08202023</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-08-20-2023-files</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[files]]></category>
            <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Cells with no data can now be unmapped using “Do not import”, if previously]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Cells with no data can now be unmapped using “Do not import”, if previously<br>
mapped to a value.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#08202023</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-08-20-2023-files</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[files]]></category>
            <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Filter: "Last Name" like A% will now retrieve all records where Last Name starts]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Filter: &quot;Last Name&quot; like A% will now retrieve all records where Last Name starts<br>
with “A”. Previously, it was retrieving records that contained “A”.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#08202023</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-08-20-2023-dataxp</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[dataxp]]></category>
            <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The continue button is now disabled on mapping scene while mappings are loading.]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>The continue button is now disabled on mapping scene while mappings are loading.<br>
This ensures user can only advance to review scene after mappings are saved.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatfile.com/changelog/platform#08202023</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">platform-08-20-2023-dataxp</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[dataxp]]></category>
            <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>